[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard
boy hello welcome to the junkyard love
podcast today's recommendations before
we get kicking off is two podcasts that
you can check out on Spotify or Apple
music or wherever else you find your
podcasts that's gonna be the align
podcasts lign align and stuff you should
know these are completely different but
they're both wonderful they both teach
you wonderful things about the world
around you your brain and your body
today we've got mica this episode was
recorded somewhere around a month ago
maybe a month and a half ago at the most
premiering now for the first time but
it's quite wonderful excited to get into
it so let's get going take care of
yourself check on your posture and
breathe from your diaphragm let's go
well we're recording hello Micah hi how
are you today I'm good how are you I'm
hanging in there I am a what we'll just
start with how I started with you you're
like how are you and I was like honestly
I'm kind of having a depression day and
I think that like I already feel better
just like we just talked about it like
you know what I mean like just being
open to where it's like and you probably
understand that I can be open about this
like I'm not maybe my own 100% today but
I'm still here you know it's a you can't
go in too many jobs or like things where
you can be like hey boss or or hey hey
customer welcome to Starbucks I'm really
[__] depressed today so if you just go
rate wasy on me you know
yeah if you could just really really be
nice today of all days also a we scoot
in give me like a fist distance and you
talk to the front of it right here like
this distance yeah that's totally good
and you can also that's the things all
you so you can manhandle it and just
move it around if you need to it is from
Amazon so it's a little on the cheap
side be a little delicate but it doesn't
matter um
Micah
shears first of all sure
you want to talk about a little bit of
your background
a little bit of because I forgot what
did we originally when we are first
messaging back and forth what was our
first like hey we should get together
and talk about this I feel like it's
branched out to so many like we just
like talking about emotions in our minds
and in all these things anyway but
camera szekely what it was at the
beginning do you I can't remember and I
don't really feel like I'm a person who
has like ADHD but when we're talking I
feel like it's kind of just done that
and it's just spiraled out and to like
so many different topics that I don't
like we can cover so much right I'm like
here take my ADHD thoughts and now you
think like me
yeah I can't remember I
know we were originally talking about an
interest in exploring more about like my
writing or
like I guess like the therapeutic
practice of it we talked about
journaling and gratitude but then from
there we kind of just talked about um
mental health which
it kind of spurs that direction a lot
with me right
yeah I'm open to any
content you want to talk about today
okay I want to talk about mental health
for sure but let's talk about riding
first so
riding is a thing we talked about just I
mean just the act of like journaling
just getting something out we were
talking about like being being our own
worst critic to like it like sometimes
you write something and you're like okay
that is like I got it like you you hit
Enter that's not because at some point
it seems like for one when you're
writing a piece like it's never really
done but at some point it's kind of like
okay I think that's less sentence right
so there's that and then
we were talking about how sometimes you
can put a piece out or like ride up like
like you you do blogs and getting your
writer than that whip put a piece out
and then like a couple months later
you're kind of like I don't know like
when I think of like it do I think
that's still like is that still what I
like do I represent I don't know you
know do you do you ever have like like
as you're going through like for me when
I'm writing I'll be discouraged like
sometimes halfway through like I'll be a
[__] I don't know if I think this even
because it's coming out how do you get
to where you can like post it but tell
me about your your posting how you get
to where you're like this is done I
finished this piece this is good enough
to submit I actually think the moment of
posting is more of an impulse
maybe it's sometimes just being tired of
like looking at it or I feel really
overzealous about it and I'm like oh I
just feel really confident about this
like I don't know why I didn't turn it
in sooner um I definitely relate to like
getting bored of something some point
through writing it I'm like I have all
these ideas and then just like my mood
deflates and I was like oh maybe I don't
really want to keep writing about that
right now and a lot of things I've
returned two months weeks years later
and ivory vamped it from there and so
there might be like seven different
variations of the same idea throughout
the different places I've saved your
posted it mm-hmm um but I guess it's
like not cooperating to fit yourself so
you always have that
yeah
writing down something for me usually if
it's a really good thought idea it takes
like the bulk of it and like one place
and I end up sitting down and writing on
that topic anywhere between like 45
minutes to like three hours sit there
writing and editing on it and it'll only
end up being
like a page maybe a page and a half but
I just have I don't know it's like
someone it's like some other part of me
takes over and helps me write mm-hmm
some other part of me is working extra
hard creatively to come up with like
those really nice words for what I'm
trying to describe or those really
profound phrases or it's definitely like
the
philosophical side of me has to be
turned on for a piece of writing to feel
valid I need to have a couple of key
phrases or lines in there that I'm like
yes I've never heard anyone describe it
that way and if this was like a tagline
for a movie um that would be it like
that would be what you pull from it it's
enough of a
thought inducing but specific enough
freezing do you ever impress yourself
like you write something or some
philosophical standing like Jesus that's
that's great do you ever yeah yeah I do
yeah that's a great feeling it's it's
hard to like you're like I don't want to
inflate that you know I don't wanna like
lock onto that but this thing is good
because it's you know you have those
feelings like because that because I
have the same thing and I'll write
something in my ah man that's juicy
that's fantastic you worded it great and
everything and then sometimes the next
day you're like you're a dumb idiot and
that word sucks like so sometimes you
gotta just like do when you have that
little like hey that's pretty good you
gotta really give that to yourself for
me anyway right and sometimes a thought
is really good but you cannot find the
perfect word for it and those are the
times that I wish that
like Google was more adaptive and you
could explain a sensation and be like
what is the word I'm actually trying to
use here that I'm maybe not aware of yet
I feel like it's probably gonna have
that soon do you think yeah algorithms
just so good I hope so because I have
that a lot even in conversation I'm like
what's the word that I'm thinking of is
it's kind of uncomfortable how often
people come to me and they ask for my
opinion on something and then I want to
describe a person or that place or my
experience with something in a very
specific way that I don't want to
mislead them by using
like typically functional words like
good or fun all right I'm gonna go it
needs to be much more specific than that
especially if I'm kind of criticizing
something because I don't want to just
knock something as that's bad or that's
a moral or I want it to kind of have
like a like a bittersweet understanding
of it because not all things are just
black or white and so I feel like
me putting so much pressure on having
words to mean something and to be
intentional when I write and when I'm
talking and what I'm doing counseling
with students it really wears on me
mentally because I just won't don't want
to put the wrong
implication out on any person's
personality or experience or
I still want other people who read my
stuff or go out and
you know
spend time with the person they were
asking about that I've already had
experiences with to build their own
opinion of it right yeah III think that
do you ever find that
like because I get impostor syndrome
I don't I think that like leans into
that sometimes the imposter syndrome of
like like sometimes you can really know
what you're talking about or like you're
talking about this thing very in-depth
at work or your fluently saying the
words and you're like oh I give this
person great advice and then sometimes
you're you go to write it and it's like
what you were trying to say and the
whole thing that you were trying to
express the whole feeling that you're
trying to like tell them it's like words
just don't get to it you know like do
you forget that like it so it's like man
like I know what I'm trying to say but
like this [__] pencil you know this
paper like it just doesn't seem to flow
what's out of my mind you know exactly
it's almost like when I learn about some
like stuff in the Eastern traditions
like look like reading like Buddhism and
Hinduism and that sort of stuff they
have words that that we don't have like
we don't have
like like the Dharma and the Dhamma and
like you Vic words that mean something
so much greater that like in America we
just want to condense it down like no
what's that mean it's like well you
can't exactly just put it in one
sentence and understand the whole thing
and then also based off of
like who you think is reading your blog
post or who you think is reading the the
long message that you send or who like
we live in such a diverse world with
everybody's like diverse ways of
understanding and comprehending things
like sometimes I feel like you have to
like alright who do I need to like well
you know it's not a mask so much but
like what like wording and what kind of
style of phrasing do I need to do or
speak of to get to these right people I
don't know if you ever had any of that
like it essentially what I'm saying is
like you ever have where it's like you
go to say something on Facebook or you
go to give someone a text but then it's
completely different kind of like person
or style of writing in words that you're
using then your blog you that yeah I try
to think about my audience especially
when I'm speaking to someone in person
or I'm texting them directly
because some people can hear my humor
because it's really dry it's really
monotone it's very sarcastic and it's
just so subtle so I'm very like
particular with who I use that with
to make sure that they're not being
misled in some way right
because I'm also serious and it's just
really hard to tell sometimes unless I
give you like a smize or I laugh and
it's but usually I don't indulge in that
I just kind of like I'm gonna let you
work that out on your own right
but you're like are you mean to me right
now can you be less me you're like no
I'm laughing I like what you said about
us not having all of the words and I've
thought a lot about how things get
translated between languages but also I
like playing the game like telephone
when we were kids and how quickly just
like a couple of words it
misunderstood and how everyone's
comprehension isn't the same or hearing
or a level of understanding or whatever
that might look like I also feel kind of
disappointed that we don't have more
ways to describe some of the most
influential ways of expressing like care
for someone like saying I care for you
or I admire you or I love you or I'm in
love with you like I don't feel like
there's enough to really incorporate how
you specifically feel about more than
that certain people because you like
it's I don't know like I think there's I
have guy friends in my life that the
cues are misread sometimes maybe on
either side and I want to tell people a
lot how much I care for them or admire
them or love them and I don't think our
society really accepts like openly doing
that without it coming out very like
hippie dippie like just walking around
like peace love happiness or whatever
and and that it's a bummer that you
can't just openly tell people with
sincerity like oh I really I really care
for you it makes him uncomfortable right
it's like a look like we don't do that
we're not talking about the real stuff
this is WWE world we're living in we
don't we don't say I love you you know
like it but but it would be nice if
there was like like a new string of
words or a new like I mean I think that
we should make it okay in our society to
say like I love you and like I feel like
my friends and I when it comes to full
mobility like it just seems like
something we improve on all the time
being able to like sincerely like I had
my friend Nate over yesterday and we had
a podcast not like I mean I'm pretty
sure that we hugged each other in like
made eye contact looked each other in
the eyes and said I love you bro like it
was this sincere like I felt that you
know and the amount of men that probably
never felt like that you know that like
you know I'm gonna feel pretty lucky you
know that like I have friends who are
willing to be so vulnerable with me and
say like hey man thanks you know I love
you I do appreciate you in my life and
stuff
what a
saying that you had to that you had a
young cat here's a situation for y'all
son he had a young cat he's 17 he's got
a manly ass dad he's like like we don't
show love in our house like we don't we
don't do that how can you like what what
would you say to him if he's like I feel
like I have like love for my friends and
I want to tell them but I don't want
them to call me gay I don't want them to
like call me call me a [__] like all
these things that that all these you
know shitty words in high school that
that are apparently so devastating for
us to hear you know what advice would
you give to a 17 year old who doesn't
know how to communicate love because
it's just kind of around a hard-ass
family oh
man put you on the spot I know
I
feel like there's a student I currently
talked to that's around that age that I
my perception of his home life growing
up is is like that and he is
he's been vulnerable enough to cry in
front of me about the things that he's
experiencing and he's one of my favorite
students that I connect with
just because he is so mature and he
tries to hold so much back but I can see
those guards coming down with me and you
know it's not exactly what you asked but
whenever he is like more vulnerable and
he's more candid and I see his guards
like not being utilized during a session
with me I just really commend him and
tell him how much I appreciate his
honesty with me and his ability to be
vulnerable in here and I know that we
don't grow up in a society that
traditionally values men being sensitive
and
sharing that with someone else and I
just tell him how much I appreciate it
and how validated he should feel for
having those feelings and
it goes over pretty well I mean you can
still see that it's hard for someone to
accept compliments when they're not used
to having someone
be so involved with them emotionally
right but if you were to try and like
take that to his friends I think he does
in subtle ways I see him becoming more
agitated by things that maybe didn't bug
him six months ago that are now kind of
like peeping up on him and he's not
vibing with his friends in the same way
and when they try to like pick little
fights with him or if they've been
drinking and I can see it bugging him
now because he's like he just doesn't
see the point of it he doesn't
understand why they can't just act like
brothers and have those harder
conversations
so I guess I just if that if it's really
important if it was really important to
that person I
would say just keep continually like
leaning in to those
desires of wanting to express and be
more of a vulnerable person around your
friends and maybe not all of them are
gonna like adhere to those kind of
things and they might kind of step back
or be weird about it or
even be intentionally like rude back at
you or in a joking way even which is
also hurtful but I think you're gonna
find that a couple of people in the
front group are gonna get on board with
that and maybe at first they'll respond
to you in the same way when you're
one-on-one right and then as soon as you
get you know more people on board of
like know where we're going to share
with back here like even
what is it I talk about all the time
with my students and tell them how
unhealthy it is self-deprecating humor
that's a huge one in today as well
deprecating humor on other people how
unfortunate it is that we utilize that
as a coping skill all the time I was
like it's so unhealthy and eventually
other people will see how good it feels
to be in your presence if you're just
constantly respectful right yeah I
really like how you said the when I was
thinking I was kind of visualizing like
the the talk with the counselor if I was
a 17 year old like I feel like the the
moment that he wouldn't realize until
you pointed it out or until you you gave
him this advice would be the like the
the moment where it's like hey if you
don't realize it right now you're you're
doing you're telling me this too right
now that's amazing like you that's a
think about you know three months ago
man you wouldn't have even told me you
would have been vulnerable in front of
me I think that like getting to the
point where you can talk to someone or
like showing tears in front of someone
like man that's actually a huge step
right there and that's a step in the
right direction
and I think I definitely want to talk
about the self-deprecating humor I feel
like that's something I love memes like
memes are [__] hilarious
comedy has never been so instantly on
our fingertips and so absolutely
hilarious like the amount of things
pretty much three times a day you can be
scrolling through Instagram but like oh
my god I didn't realize it but I have
that same exact thought all the time and
that's hilarious I'm a piece of [__]
like it's like this joking thing in it
it's it's hard because this stuff is
genuinely like hilarious like even if
it's like like I care about other people
but there will be ones that are making
fun of other people that I'm like I
can't help but laugh you know and it's
it's like it's this thing that I noticed
when I when I quit social media for you
that's like one thing that you know it
like oh like a lot of my friends I would
stay in contact with them during the
week because we'd send you know memes
back and forth and we're just like kinda
we have our own little humor we made a
lien for and we would just send back
kind of the same typical whatever and
it's all great but I think that when it
comes to mental health it's not not a
really good thing to jokingly make fun
of yourself every day or even try to
find things that you can make fun of
easily and other people every day
and what do you think about what's your
perspective on like memes in the kind of
culture around like the self-deprecating
memes I guess I think there's a lot of
little fine lines and I also think it's
about getting comfortable with the
things that you don't like about
yourself and making a choice as to
whether or not you actually want to
change them like I have it on my water
bottle and I don't remember what TED
talks so I'm not sure who to give credit
to
it was about career choices actually but
it ended up being really
mental health directed and it'syou can
either choose unconditional love and
acceptance or change at any time in your
life that's like your only two options
only two good options you know and
unconditionally love yourself and accept
yourself or decide to make a change or
something that you can unconditionally
love and accept because the other
alternative is just being miserable
yeah I like that a lot the amount of
work is kind of the same because you're
gonna keep thinking and ruminating on it
you can either be ruminating on the fact
that you're like well I am trying to
work on that and sometimes I lapse in
judgment or sometimes I do like driving
here I
went out of turn for like a threeway
stop and I was like I'm so stupid and
I'm like
out loud like verbally I still do that
and I have to really think and some I
have to add like a sometimes or you know
I don't get it yet like I preach that to
gets to adding yet on the end of
something just because you can kind of
save the thought and be like yeah well I
said the thing but I'm not saying it's
definite right I'm you know I'm not
always on my guard like I'd like to be
are not always making positive growth
choices but I can be like I'm working on
it though I think it's not yeah I
noticed that I mean just the noticing of
like you didn't just let yourself feel
that like how you're an idiot for going
out of your turn on that three-way stop
you you noticed that you were trying to
like feel bad to yourself think you're
trying to say like hey you know you suck
or whatever in this way I think that
that moment of noticing always like just
like putting a pin in that you know like
that's all you need to do so that moment
of noticing and then what you know you
don't have to like hold on to it you can
make okay a little mad at myself for
that but that's okay I'm just I'm
changing like I you know I'm working on
it like maybe I'm not the best driver
that's okay you know whatever yeah let
yourself off the hook as much as you can
morally do so I feel like that's kind of
the line that I like to you know don't
don't let yourself off the hook for bad
things that you know you need to fix or
correct or apologize for to feel better
but little things like that um there's
so much that's not illegal like I know
we have all these new laws and stuff but
in a very real way like Washington state
laws or federal laws there's so much
that's not illegal that I don't know why
we incorporate so much guilt and shame
into our life if there's not
like
like a philosophical or a federal law
that's telling you like that's a no-no
like you're not supposed to do that you
know you don't need police officers
constantly like in your face for like
why didn't I just do the dishes last
night it really wasn't that tired or why
didn't I just let that person go instead
of being you know maybe feeling like
selfish about going first I
just think about that a lot how much we
feel guilty for or shame ourselves for
or make fun of ourselves and use
self-deprecating humor and it's like for
what does anybody really listening like
most the time we're by ourselves who we
trying to make laugh yeah it's it's
unimportant if things still get done or
you feel like you still have the
opportunity to make an amend or
you really do agree with what you said
even if it didn't come out the nicest
you don't have to completely back step
and be like oh well I shouldn't have
said that you can just be like mmm my
heart was in the right place and I
should have phrased it differently um
I I talk to kids a lot about not
apologizing for things that you're not
sorry for like it's not transparent and
you shouldn't do it Rachel Rachel Hollis
talks about that - yeah I like I mean it
sounds kind of [__] but like sorry not
sorry it's just a shorter way of saying
I'm not really apologetic for what I
said because it's how I feel
but either I could have setup more
respectfully or I could have asked if
you wanted my opinion first
but if you did ask for my opinion and
you weren't happy about it you know I
I'm not gonna in just the way I open
that door I can't like like you said I
got a spike it you know like it's if
someone's saying like a help me then you
don't get to choose the way that it's
helped sometimes you know right
yeah I think that we do get to the the
sorry not sorry thing I think we I see
that too much in like like the mean girl
world like where they like they just
love that saying right I guess I'm
saying they as if I'd like you know an
entire group or something but uh but
just like the it's not about being rude
and it's not about like
like just plowing over people and like
being like well I'm just I'm focusing on
myself and I'm being the best version
myself and all that like just [__]
stepping on people that's not how it
works but I think like yeah not always
apologizing not always
even the you know give the little
apologies I mentioned Rachel Hollis she
like like if you're late apologizing or
if you bump into someone saying sorry or
if like these you realize the word sorry
I mean that that's a word that a lot of
us get into saying more than we say any
other word like as soon as you're in the
presence of another one I probably you
know what I'll ask you about this I
don't this could be just something that
I'm I just watched birds of prey and I
just I've been talking a lot about like
the masculine feminine energy that's
going on in society
do you feel as a woman do you feel that
you like not knowingly but like do you
feel like you like apologize to men more
like like if you like bump into them or
something like it did you feel that very
much so you want to talk about that I've
gone through phases especially working
and serving industry when I was working
at Silver Star where I felt like I
always take a backseat when I'm walking
in public places to me adjusting where
I'm at if someone is like possibly going
to run into me whether it's they're not
paying attention because they're on
their phone or they're simply just not
acknowledged like how close their bodies
about to be to my body that I will move
to the right or to the left or stop or
you know reposition myself and for a
while I was like that's really great
because I'm just I'm just I'm so aware
of where my body is and I'm just being
respectful of other people but then I
kind of got to a point especially
working in a bar that I was like screw
that why do I have feet moving like I
have a tray full of cups or drinks or
like I'm the only person that really
needs to get from point A to point B
right now to provide service and people
are standing in like circling in
pathways and walkways and so I stopped
moving out of the way and I actually had
people to spill their drinks on me I had
drinks that I had on trays spill and I
let other people be sorry for a change
I'm like well maybe you should pay
attention to where you're going it
shouldn't have to be on me you know and
I struggle with road rage a little bit
and so occasionally I think the same
thing in cars and I was like that I
don't really want to have to deal with
like damages if I decide to like be like
you don't just ram into people
but you know there might come a day just
watch out you can see you on the road
you just gonna rant like I'm not oh my
blanket was on first let's see who
happens yeah but I feel like it's a
choice now that I'm aware of that
especially when it comes to like moving
where I'm at when I'm around people or
and I'm in a crowd if I'm taking the
back seat and I'm being more submissive
and I'm just choosing to be respectful
and be like alright I'm just gonna make
sure that I don't you know have anything
spill on me today or I'm not gonna bump
into anyone and then there are other
days that I'm like you know it I don't
understand why more people aren't making
that conscientious choice it's it's
crazy and I don't like using gender
stereotypes at all but I do feel like
it's usually whether it's like a height
thing it seems to be more men and women
it seems like women will be distracted
on their phones but they will happen to
like look up just in the nick of time
and they'll like move and then they'll
do that to me and look I'm sorry like
for almost touching me right um so it's
just I don't know it's just one of those
little things that once now that I've
noticed it and it sounds like you kind
of think about it I know there are other
people I've talked to about it um
it's it's silly but it still feels
important or like it's the principle
sometimes it's it's it's not so much
about like getting up in arms and like
hey like you know what you should be the
one to say sorry it's not so much that
it's kind of like like a like you
noticed that it's like hey like that
everybody who wasn't a jerk kind of just
kept aware up the people around them and
like didn't want to bump into like oh
and if I'm the one in this chicken we're
walking towards each other situation and
it's more logical for me to move I'll
step out of the way you'd think that
like everybody thinks like that I think
you know working in a bar you probably
definitely experience like oh no these
people are just just so folk you know
drunk of course but but just so focused
on themselves I think that I am I
I don't know I think that I've always
kind of been the
like I'll step out of your way as well
but I think that it's probably like my
my upbringing my I did a lot of walking
like it's walk to school in the morning
walk home from school walk to work walk
home from work all these things so is
pretty much like a very aware of like
where I'm at when someone's coming up on
the sidewalk and I'm like it's just
something that I've always been crazy
aware of like where I'm walking and not
being other people's way in these things
but you you realize that not everybody
thinks like that and there's people who
are just walking completely thinking
about themselves the entire time it's
not supposed to be maybe a selfish thing
but they're like they're blowing past
other people you know it's a so some
guys are living their life as if they're
the monster-truck and in women and in
small people are just kind of like the
[__] little cars and in the field you
know um
yeah that's interesting I think noticing
it though I think like just
not a lot of us can can take down our
importance or our sense of our sense of
importance in public situations like
when our chest is so out and our tough
guy is so on that it's like like if you
bump into me I'm gonna give you a look
to make sure you're not a guy trying to
bump up against me in that way because
I'll [__] you up you know it's okay
you're being so tough but your ended up
like you're taking out people who are
not trying to intimidate you people are
just trying to live their life you know
I just think it's huge to be watching
out or where you're going you know like
don't over obsess about it think about
yourself but like watch out for people
you know yeah and I think some of it is
made worse by cell phones I feel like it
probably wasn't that way 25 years ago um
you know manners have changed around
what's decent to do around other people
and how much your attention should be
focused on them or looking up or where
you should be walking mm-hmm as a female
I pay attention when I'm on dates if you
have the opportunity to walk on a
sidewalk next to your date if the guy is
on the outside and I really don't care
so much um
because I feel like I'm perfectly
capable and I'm pretty aware you know
when you walk by yourself I mean you can
walk on whichever side you want right
but I do think it's a nice thing to see
men are that are aware of that and I
would never complain about it or be like
OOP switch me sides like be a gentleman
but I do take notice yeah it's nice to
know that they thought about that right
and you know for the ones that don't do
that maybe their family didn't teach
them that way and so it's not like
they're not a gentleman they're just
maybe not a gentleman in that way
because it wasn't taught um but there
has been like some that are on the other
side of it and they were taught and they
just don't do it and I'm like oh
it's a huge thing in my head I don't
know I wonder if I was taught I must
have been taught at a young age that
because that's definitely that's been
huge in my mind like if like Shane and I
will walk to the store and I'll be
switching sides of her like it's not a
short it's a short walk but I'll be like
switching sides to make sure I'm just
it's like this automatic thing where I'm
on the outside but it's kind of a it's a
silly thing but I think it is more of a
gesture it's like a it's almost one of
those things we were talking about like
there's not words for but what I'm doing
is I'm not trying to like a certainty
dominance or anything it's kind of like
a there's a gesture towards the woman
towards the person you're walking with
of like hey I'm thinking about you right
now yeah I can hear the Brio yeah I'm
looking out for you just so you know
like if a car comes out
that car up you know thank you boy he'll
kill me first you know this thing you
could stop a car with your hand or
something yeah and anyone who is
older than the person next to them or
like if it's a child specifically anyone
should take that role and be on the
outside with a child or a pet like we
should for people who this is not clique
in their brain we should explain what
this is actually we should like for the
people who are like what are you talking
about so as a as a man there's like a
thing where it's a safety thing I think
you know you walk the side nearest the
car so if you're on a sidewalk the woman
would walk on the inside and it's kind
of it's a gesture of like I don't know
like do we really think the cars going
to hit skip the curb or what do you
think on this with it I've seen some
crazy wrecks and there have been some
like vehicle malfunctions lately with
them crashing the buildings oh yeah so I
mean anything is possible I simply think
just you know talking about bad driving
for like the bad drivers out there that
miscalculated if they're gonna hit a
curb or not or if they took a corner too
closely um putting you know the
masculine person the male and the
relationship on the curb has just been
an act of safety for like women or like
I don't know maybe it came from like a
like a misogynist place like let the
women window shop while we walk
put her on the inside but they kind of
like change the script on they're like
hey maybe this sounds better for being
men but
yeah I don't know I don't I wonder where
that got established or I mean as soon
as we had streets and roads or like was
there like a kind of a gentleman
courtesy back in like the olden days to
like you know of like a like what would
a lion do like if there's like cuz I
feel like you know a female lion is just
as badass as a male lion in so many ways
alright I'm just trying to think of like
there's like okay there's a predator
over there like it's the male gonna just
out of instinctual like like if this
other lion tries to attack our family
sort of such Ottoman line works really
positioning yeah positioning yourself
like I don't maybe it is like a an
intuitive like evolution thing even I
think I do think it is and there's a lot
of psychology behind
positioning and I learned about this
when I was getting my bachelor's and I
found it really interesting we talked
about a proximity and positioning
based on what you want to get out of
something in a classroom so people who
sit in the back are trying to look more
laid-back like it's an impression that
you're wanting to give or people who sit
closest to the door maybe have anxiety
or PTSD and they need that escape like
you position yourself you know where you
feel most comfortable in a classroom or
when you're at a bar or a restaurant
like I think a lot of people instincts
really do that and then when you're with
a person I think you're always making
choices and I feel like I'm kind of like
I get anxious so I think about weird
outcomes of things and I like to know
where the exits are and that doesn't
have any attachment to like PTSD or
anything like that I'm just trying to
have a game plan in case chaos kind of
broke loose for some reason mm-hm
when you're with someone else you take
into account like am I putting myself
first am i putting them first and so
when you're walking with someone you
know taking the outside towards the road
no matter who you are you're kind of
choosing them over you in a way you're
thinking that's the safest place for a
person to be is on the inside yeah it
does actually communicate communicate
quite a bit you know if you're paying
attention like that it's interesting to
point out and it's also the thing about
where you choose in the classroom like
because I was definitely like in the
back but my thing has always been I have
to go to see the door I have to be able
to be facing the door like my back can't
be to the door because I don't like
being snuck up on
but like it's interesting I've actually
you know in my healing process and in my
like okay that's how I am but I noticed
that it would start to distract me like
oh we went to the we went to the
dermatitis center we went to that
concert and
like where I was we're kind of we're on
the side and we're just right in the
front front of the stands there so I can
see everybody in general admission and
everybody who's like walking it doesn't
have a chair you know they're standing
in front so I can see them and that's
not too bad but the corner of my eye
right here on the right side was the
entrance for all of them and there's a
bar and this is people going in and out
in and I literally could not I couldn't
focus on this on the [__] stage
because I couldn't let myself get rid of
like these people the corn Amaya like I
always had to make sure it's like a like
way like you have a gun to you like yeah
you know it's not like I'm really I'm
not I didn't actually think I was in
danger I what it was just a an intuitive
thing that's always turned on for me of
I can't really if there's a distraction
on the corner my eye of like people or
like things that like I don't really
know who you are what you're doing or
you know movement
it's interesting but I think that over
time that was more recent and I noticed
it but over time when we go to
restaurants and we go to eat somewhere
or when she and I sit down she knows
that I'm like that and she know like
she'll usually pick the one where were
my back's not to the door but actually I
have because I'm sick and I'm sick of
being in a fight or flight when I'm just
trying to be really experienced this
moment with with the person I'm with so
I've actually been making the choice to
have my back to the door and it's a I
can feel it's it's a little it's nervous
I don't like it at first but then before
I know and I forget you know I forget
and I'm having a conversation
and because because a lot of times when
you kind of do things based off of fear
like you get to the back of the
classroom or you you do choose that seat
nearest the the door
you are deciding like like be ready for
this thing sort of right and it's almost
this like you're you're looking for
something you you you're not fully
present with that moment right it's a
it's a we're protecting ourselves but it
can be non-beneficial it's very accurate
your body is always
trying to keep itself safe your body
wants to preserve itself your body wants
to stay alive your body is always acting
on instinct and of things raised four
little red flags here make you nervous
your body is always encouraging you to
sink back into your comfort zone do what
it means to protect yourself and so when
you step outside that bubble it's very
intentional you're choosing to do
something that makes you a little bit
nervous you're choosing to go outside
your comfort zone it's a choice and
sometimes that choice is for other
people you know and so I just think
that's something that people don't think
about that comfort is what comes
naturally comfort is so hard to fight
with and challenge back and forth and be
like I'm gonna take time away from you
because it's everything in your body
says no don't do that thing I want to
remain safe
and so it's hard you have to train
yourself to yeah try to challenge
yourself to step outside of that and
tell yourself you know when you get
those nervous anxious feelings like
there's a good percentage I'm okay but
there's gonna be like a 90% chance that
I'm gonna be okay doing this you know
unless it's not some like crazy extreme
sport that has like no boundaries but
it's tourney guys against a rug rugby
field right
yeah I mean I used to watch when I was
younger a thousand ways to die and there
was some weird things on there just like
off the wall I go I never thought about
that being a possibility no I do but if
we think about how much chaos and
destruction and opportunities there
really are to like injure ourselves in a
day if we're not careful if we're
totally clumsy you know if we woke up
everyday drunk and we had no other
choice or on psychedelics and tried to
like
configure our way around you know a
moving platform even like um
we really do okay most people day to day
like the fact that we don't constantly
get paper cuts or we don't break fingers
and toes every month like it's kind of
crazy how
strong and invincible our bodies are
most of the time we're pretty soft and
fragile man like have you ever worked it
like a machinery like a mill somewhere
where it's like like at all times it's
like like I worked at warehouser I'm
like dude at any point I can reach my
arm into this thing and it will not even
skip a beat it will rip my arm off with
all the skin and it will not miss a beat
like we have we have so many little
things that we have done to protect
ourselves and like learn about like in
their natural things now like the paper
cut thing like wit and we'd come across
a lot of paper and we never get paper
cuts mm-hmm we've we've gotten this down
pretty well but I think we need to there
is a lot of places in it for me anyway
there was places where I'm like man my
my guards up too much my guard is up too
much armour has been on too long I I am
in a safe environment and and my partner
safe and I don't need to be watching the
door the whole time I could think about
Olive Garden I can think about these
breadsticks you know like you don't have
to be are in fear
what do you remember what got you into
like psychology and studying the mind in
emotions and stuff and like what what
first part that you remember um a lot of
little things
probably the biggest thing was a
suggestion from my grandma she and I are
super close I know we talked about that
first time we met up
she
she was the one who raised me for my
kindergarten school year so like my
first big year at school and she had all
this extra time I'm I think they were
retired already both my grandparents and
so they were just always around teaching
me like school on top of school but not
in like an annoying way and I think my
grandma really helped me build my like
social-emotional piece of myself and
always allowed that patience for me to
learn and make errors and you know when
I made mistakes at Grandma's house like
I didn't flinch or worried that I was
gonna get yelled at she'd be like oh
well what happened here and so I really
learned and developed that from her and
so I would go to school because she
would make me second-guess like why bad
things happen and try to come up with
like a silver lining as to like you know
there needs to be there's some good that
comes out of bad - there's lessons and
so I would come home from school and I
would tell her about the children that
were like particularly like naughty just
like bad behavior screamers
hitting friends you know using foul
language whatever it might be and I come
home and I got to the point with her
that I would start coming home and
instead of just complaining to me like
well this kid is just nuts like I don't
want to be their friend they scare me I
come home and be like well I wonder if
their parents yelled at them yesterday
or I wonder if they didn't have
breakfast and so she really helped me
change the script on like I don't I
can't begin to understand why a person
is acting shitty today I don't know
maybe if I ask them they still wouldn't
tell me the truth maybe they don't even
so just assuming that people are
inherently good and they just make
mistakes and maybe something happened um
and it was an off day because you're
still getting to know these kids and
we're young and so powerful are young
age I took that with me um I did well
enough in school I got honors or like at
least like a of a 3.0 but nothing really
particularly hit like I liked writing
and I like literature and I liked
reading and
but it wasn't what I wanted to focus on
and I didn't like being told what to do
with my writing um
very like respectfully defiant
but when it came time to do Running
Start I took a lot of psychology courses
because she said well if you don't want
to be a nurse cuz that was what she
wanted for me she's like maybe you
should go into psychology because you've
always tried to understand why people do
the things they do and why you do the
things you do and how you can
understand both them and yourself better
and so I just kind of took it and ran
with it and classes were hard classes
were intense but they were usually
interesting and I would be able to apply
everything I learned in my classes and
my waking life my normal life and I just
even if I don't end up continuing to
pursue careers and psychology fields I
can use it in any career field and I
still hold on to that
like I I don't know it's just it's such
an interest of mine that I never stopped
researching or growing out of just pure
and trinsic motivation to do so in that
realm yeah so I feel like I would have
been doing myself a disservice to go to
college for business or medicine
unless I tumble major it because it's
just that's where my heart was at the
time and sometimes I knock myself
because the pay is not good for this
career choice um
but I really like it and I get a lot out
of it and I feel like I've matured a lot
faster just because of a fascination in
it right and it's
actually coming like full circle you
said something or posted something about
like four months ago that
you weren't meaning to like come off
bold I don't think but I got really
defensive about it and whenever I get
defensive I like to think about like why
am i defensive like his act is it
actually encroaching on my morals my
ethics my beliefs or is it because it's
something I need to work on and do
better and the thing that you said I
can't remember the exact words verbatim
but you were talking about like why if
someone has studied psychology and
mental health still suffer with it like
was kind of like the thought you were
having and I'm like and I got frustrated
by that because I do struggle with it
still and I'm like why study it and like
I should you know but I just really sat
with it and I'm like that's kind of the
point is like you never really get you
never really get to like understand
mental health like you can have answers
you can have tools or solutions or
understanding and awareness but you
never really get to like know it it's
not like solving a math problem where
you're like oh there's one answer to
this math problem I'll send you feel
better oh that's the answer cool blue
skies right and I think some people
really strive for that and they need
that and they need that consistency of
like there is a problem and there is a
solution you know and mental health is
like
there's both sometimes not both like
it's kind of just this like shoulder
shrug like I don't know oh
okay I want to I want to unpack my
arrogance they're
trying to think cuz I mean we can talk
about that this morning like I was
saying like well this is something I
tell Shaylee like today for example is
you know I woke I was just just not a
great day for me in my head
but what would I get so frustrated about
is I'm such like I can handle it I can
do this I can [__] find the answer
like I will do it give me ten hours
close that door you you come in in ten
hours I'm gonna have this salt like
that's who I am and like when it comes
to mental health it's like it doesn't
work like that it's so frustrating like
for me um I can be talking to Shaylee
this morning when I was talking to
Shelly about it and I'm like I know the
answers okay like I know like it's not
logical for me to be thinking these
things and in the end to feel better I
know that I'm gonna go outside and do
physical activity it'll kind of pull me
out of that state and then I'll be able
to like I know like what I can do but
you can't just hear these things you
can't just all of a sudden like it's
like
like you don't become God just by
reading some [__] in the Bible you know
like you don't you know you know the
difference between the words in the
conceptualization of like okay I think I
understand that and then like the actual
knowing understanding and knowing
there's like a huge gap there and
that's crazy I wonder what I'm trying to
think of like what I want what more I
was saying in the situation because it I
feel like I
of how much time is just a lot of stuff
that I'm like aggressively sprouting on
on Facebook or like on my pedestal about
is like I'm ten hours deep into the
content of what I think other people are
like Nicki like it's it's almost like my
social media sometimes with what I'm
saying is aggressive and I understand it
because I'm like
like I'm starting the conversation
halfway through they don't know what I
was just reading what I'm talking about
exactly so they just get like that part
I'm getting better at clarifying that I
guess but I think it was just a really
it was a really good thought and I like
I've grown to like the things that make
me defensive because it doesn't sit and
like eat at me anymore for most things
um
I'm still growing I'm human but
it makes it really draws my attention to
like the like the Robin Williams quote
like when the bad things happen it draws
your attention to the good things you
weren't paying attention to
so like when I get defensive about
something it draws my attention to
something that has bugged me but maybe
that has been lessened over time like
maybe it doesn't sit with me as long or
I'm like well I have really made strides
in this area it's now it's just kind of
a thought that I can allow to pass and
now we're working on just getting rid of
that thought I was kind of thinking of a
metaphor for like
I don't know like
positive feelings of self-worth and your
value and like good solid wellness and
mental health is kind of like trying to
like hold sand like you don't get to
keep it the whole time it's gonna fall
through the cracks and if someone comes
over and like smacks your hand from
underneath and all the sand falls off of
it you know you're gonna be angry like
you can be rattled you can be shaken you
can be tested you can't just hold things
for yours to keep and expect nothing to
fall out or to lessen and so you know
they preach in elementary schools like
to be bucket fillers for yourself and
for others and I think that's my
self-care is so important because like
if it is like sand and it is false or
your fingers and you don't get to
control it
you just have to keep filling it like if
a bucket had a hole in it just keep
filling the bucket so that it's never
totally empty instead of being like oh
well things just aren't going my way
there's a hole in my bucket so I'm just
gonna eventually not have sand and
that's fine like it's such I feel like
if you put it that way it's like so
obvious they're like just keep I don't
know I mean maybe someday we'll figure
out a way to like stop that so it
doesn't happen but if it doesn't do you
really just like lay down and give it up
and say oh that's just I'm gonna let
today be a shitty day like no just
decide to laugh decide to make it easier
on yourself because we don't get to move
time
faster or slower you mean you still have
to experience what you're going on
that's a you know it's that resonates
with me because I had a conversation
with my mom yesterday about
like my my family just has like a
history of like mental breakdowns and
like really bad depression and all this
stuff and I was talking about mom
yesterday she says like her mom did it
and my mom like my mom like you know we
dealt with like a lot of stuff when I
was younger and that was her she's kind
of checked out she just kind of broke
down it was like I'm done being a mom
sort of thing
the inn it was essentially I was kind of
like talking about like what
like that feeling of like it follows
fills I can just give up I can let my
bucket empty right and I was like like
do you know so that's like I feel it
like you can take a look at that like
like why do I think that it's okay to
just let my hands go and say you know
what [__] it all I'm gonna I'm gonna let
my bucket be empty and I'm gonna lay on
the ground and and I'm not gonna pick
myself up and in these things and uh you
know it sparked some interesting
thoughts between her and I but I think
that you know I've had to tell myself
it's something that I have had now that
I haven't that I have you know
I moved like a huge will to live now you
know like my depression isn't sometimes
it really [__] kicks my ass but it's
not nearly as bad as it used to be to
where I was just very debilitating I
didn't have I
dreamt of that empty bucket you know
like I was just like that's
what I'm saying is I think that like
removing that as as an option like it
like looking at that like hey that's a
thought that like I could just give up
like that is a thought itself like
that's that's not like a viable option
um and I think what life is a lot of the
times is is filling your bucket even
having the faith that you don't know how
to repair that that hole in that bucket
right now but if you just keep filling
that bucket and keep out just keep you
know keep going and you're going to
learn how to block that hole you're
gonna learn like okay there is a hole
here in this bucket something's coming
out like I don't have the right tools
the right emotional tactics to handle
these things but I think having the
faith that right yeah
I don't have it yet yeah but you can't
just like give up on it yeah because I
mean realistically I feel like it it is
such a morbid thought and like suicide
rates are high I guess um
just the mentality that I mean that
really is honestly always a choice if
people really want to choose it but
again like I said it's a choice like are
you really I don't know I get so stuck
on like don't don't be a victim to
circumstance like don't be a victim to
what other people say about you you can
you know you can experience it don't
fall victim to it don't let it become
you don't just give up and throw in the
towel and act like you know it's all
everyone else's fault that you are the
way you are that's not true it's a
choice you gave up you chose to be
miserable like I'm sorry that's just the
way it is you always have the choice to
try you know to try and save yourself to
try and be better to work through it and
I think the middle ground to that is
just taking days to be in your own space
with yourself if you need it like if you
feel like you can't handle with the
world's throwing at you you know maybe
that is a day that you lay in bed all
day then you listen to music and it's
kind of like the middle ground like you
don't always have to be out there like
fighting the good fight if you feel like
you're just exhausted but you also don't
have to like sit there ruminating on the
bad circumstances that are around you
and continuing like to perpetuate them
and doing nothing about it right
so yeah I mean I feel like the biggest
stride that I mean maybe other people
only reason I want to say this is
because I think it might make other
people feel better is that when it comes
to mental health I think the biggest
start of all is going from thinking that
suicide or just like total decline
thinking it as like a plan B or a plan Z
or whatever and just deciding that it's
not an option it's not an option you
want things to happen as they occur
naturally so yeah at some point you know
if you're really sad like your natural
time will come to pass but
choosing to like choosing that that is
the way letting it happen naturally so
everything between then and now that
unknown date is you making the best out
of what you think you can work with
right yeah I really like that you said
it is about it not being an option like
removed removing that option from the
table I think it's kind of what I did at
some point I was like it's not like I'm
not doing that I'm not going to bring
that pain to the people in my life I'm
not going to and you know you want to do
it for yourself but at that moment that
was like people first yeah that's you
know I think I said this I had this long
Facebook post this was years ago but in
a got misconstrued because you know it's
it's it's typing and I come out
aggressive sometimes and but it was it
was essentially like this long thing
about like listen like if you don't love
yourself if you don't care about
yourself if you hate yourself if you
you're like why would I do better I
don't deserve to be bit like these
things like because sometimes you can
and I know very well you can get so far
down that it's like any sort of like
positive influence towards yourself is
just [__] ridiculous you want to
laugh at it you're just like yeah that
guy doesn't deserve that like it you you
know because people's brains can get
like this but the post was essentially
like well you know if you don't have it
for yourself like think about your
friends and it's not about thinking
about their pain so much as like like do
it for your friend like you
you do bring value to their life like
how do you bring value to their life you
could if you died if you end your life
you bring sorrow and pain to your
friends and this is a hard thing because
it gets it gets messy there you don't
want to put that [__] self hurt self
self-worth you know but I do I think
that in moments where you just you admit
you just can't give any love to yourself
if you just let yourself think about a
couple of your good friends and you
think about you know their mom and their
dad and you think about your friend and
you think about how 10 years ago he was
just kind of a young turd and you think
about five years before that he was a
young kid and you think about their
whole life and I think that you can
start to
find value in
this is worst case scenario if you have
no self-worth for yourself I think that
you can find value in just the life of
the people around you and be like okay I
don't have really any self-worth here I
don't really have any like will like I I
don't think that I'm super cool but I do
have people in my life that their life
you know I could be a good person for
them I could improve myself I can get up
off the ground because like my friend
Jimmy is probably one of the coolest
people I know and like it would make me
feel really good to buy him a beer
tomorrow or it would make me if I could
if I'm available to watch my friends
Cindy's hid when she's on a work trip
like that I bring value to Cindy's life
and her in her kid's life you know
these are stretch but essentially my
facebook post was a
was it's hard to understand but I think
some people might have resonated like if
you don't have it for you you could just
think about other people like like serve
your friends like get better for other
people and that's not something that you
really want to hear like first like kids
you want to get better for yourself
first and foremost but I think that some
people get so dark and I know for a fact
because I did you get so deep that
you're like why the [__] would I do
anything for myself I'm the one who
screwed all this up you know I'm the one
who whatever like these foolish thoughts
that were stuck in the groove you know
yeah that was a post that I had a while
back oh but I like doing it for other
people it brings up some really good
points though
people who are depressed or struggle
with anxiety and like bipolar disorder
and all sorts of things they really get
pegged as a narcissistic or
only thinking of themselves or them as
the center of their universes but really
there's so much guilt tied in with not
wanting to burden other people with
their condition and so when they're
ditching plans and being flaky and
people are having to make special
adjustments for them you know they
it makes you want to refrain from it
like experiencing things with other
people because you don't want to take
away or you know make you have special
treatment because you don't feel like
you deserve it at that time but I've
seen a lot of people who have mental
health stuff going on it's particularly
women just because that's my experience
with it but come out of it like women
who go into a pregnancy depressed come
out and they don't have postpartum and I
just think that's kind of like a crazy
thing like having something else to care
about having someone else to care about
and it happened so instinctually oh yeah
it like removes it and it alleviates it
from them and so if you don't have a
child in your life and a reason to do
that maybe it's a grandparent maybe it's
younger sibling maybe it's a friend and
I think that's where you're kind of
going with that it has to become about
other people for a while because you
don't have that self-worth and you don't
have that self-love and so you can't
motivate yourself to do things for
yourself and then validate that practice
yet but you can validate it for
available to other people and
when someone who struggle with mental
health is strong enough and gets really
good at
empathizing because they've been there
or they still are there
you really begin to realize that someone
who's depressed earnings and anxiety
bipolar disorder isn't in our Cystic at
all they can really meet other people
where they're at when they're low and
maybe they can't you know be at a higher
vibration with people sometimes because
they have that mental health piece going
on that's not always up to par but they
can certainly always meet someone where
they're at because they understand it
and what I just think sometimes like
what would the world.we be and now if we
went back in time where there was no
understanding of mental health and
everyone was just either like
the coolest thing ever like that over
confidence that people just had to have
because it was like there was no other
option yeah um
I'm really grateful that society now is
kind of reaching a point where we're
really validating like meeting people
where they're at and we're trying to
find the humility and things again and
preaching like empathy it's so important
to have empathy for others that word has
come up so much on my podcast I love it
just not I don't know just thinking for
a second outside of yourself maybe this
person is experiencing something that
I'm never gonna get to understand or I'm
never gonna know the answer to but
choosing to believe that they're not
intentionally being in an unsavory way
yeah I think yeah right you know I think
that it's hard for our brain to fully
comprehend but I think like a lot of
like the Buddhism stuff that that I read
is it has made me
like
it's a fact in like you could say the
sentence but there does start to become
this understanding this comprehending
and I began to see it and like total
strangers like I see that I I see this
light in myself when I see it right
strangers but um just this fact of like
nobody wants to suffer there's nobody is
it do you know anybody who's like I
[__] love suffering I love not having
a bed to go home at night like it's so
great to sleep outside and be cold like
no man they you know they're like when
you talk to them they're you know even a
lot of times their their ego is
defending their body they're like their
egos defending their actions their he
you know they don't want to be
embarrassed it's already an embarrassing
situation like just think about a
homeless person like want to be homeless
they want love a human wants love a
human wants to love themselves more than
anything and there's clearly some things
that have caused that person in their
life to like like not be able to feel
that love for themselves and in I don't
know I feel like like as I progressed
and as I keep like reading all these
things it's like a genuine like
I get you know virtue signal signaling
like I'm so much more compassionate than
everybody but it really is profoundly
like you start to see the world in a
different way when you could really just
look at everybody who's suffering and
just be like like they just want love
like they just they truly want love at
the core of their being
it's kind of hard when we get so far
fetched you know we have like you know
politicians and like all these things
that we see in the news right of like
that [__] I just mean whatever
but at the core of their being they they
want love you know
yeah it's it's super interesting let's
uh I want to back up to to your writing
a little bit more we were talking about
you you were like down on yourself
because you like submitted something in
it in it it didn't get accepted but I
was like hey do you realize that I think
about submitting stuff all the time and
like I don't even get [__] done to where
it's submitted bull like you're
like it like you were you were
discouraging to yourself but like you're
already you're doing just fine like
you're like getting to the point of
actually submitting like okay well I'm
gonna I'm gonna put this to where people
can read it online right guy I'm gonna
people this isn't now available this is
my words from my head and now people can
like have it and use it like that's a
huge step that's like that that's a huge
thing
and when was the do you remember the
first time like how long ago it was
since you first like posted or like
finish something to where you're like
I'm gonna put that for the world can
read it remember that I think the first
time I posted something online or like
on my personal blog probably would have
been within
like
five to like seven years ago sometime
towards the end of high school that's
longer than I thought but the first time
that I actually submitted it to em
they get another website to be
represented by you know an actual
business was November of last year so
that's been like really short term yeah
was it a freeing feeling when he hit
submit or like was it like it I don't
know it was kind of like hitting submit
was
it was like not a big feeling when I hit
submit um it felt very like oxidase
achill or something I was just like huh
okay well I do think this is good and I
finally figured out how to do it and I
just hit summit and then I went about my
day and I did other things it was like a
Saturday or a Sunday afternoon um but
when I didn't know how long it would
take to get rejected or accepted or to
get the email from them that says it's
on the site I didn't even know what the
process really looked like so um when I
got the email
gosh it was the week of my birthday
actually it was a Tuesday and I just
gotten off work and I was going to my
friend Kelsey's house and I got my
emails and I was deleting them before I
went into her house just sitting in my
car and when I saw the little hot emoji
is that I think it's like a fire emoji
that says like your article has been
submitted to a thought catalog and I saw
that and I literally like started like
screaming and like oh yeah like I have I
haven't been that excited about
something and maybe like a decade
honestly just I don't think I've ever
experienced
that I can remember like now that
feeling of just like utter happy that
something of mine got published in some
way and that's what I realized like you
know it lasted for about an hour I was
very excited very happy and I wanted
everyone else to match my emotion so I
you know I told Kelsey and I told a few
people in that hour called my parents
and sent them the link can you know
about hour and hour half later I was
sitting there with myself and I'm like
oh
now that means we feel like we're gonna
be really let down if the next one
doesn't get accepted and like and I just
I started to realize how important it
was to me to get my writing out there
and I get really stuck sometimes I'm
thinking like I'm only making baby steps
or like there are lots of days where I
don't write in a row anything and I
watch Gary Vee and I'm like oh I should
be pushing myself harder like I should
be a real go-getter about this and it
just maybe I'm just like not there yet
you know I just like the I like the
relaxed benefit of just being able to
write on my own accord when I feel
passionately when I feel like I have the
words when I feel like that
philosophical creative side of me is
like really activated and submitting at
my leisure because I don't have any
writing deadlines and you know in the
back of my head I kind of hold hope that
someday I will because that's where the
big deals are thank you but right now I
like that I don't I feel like I have so
much else in my life so much personal
work that I'm just trying to like shovel
through that's just like falling leaves
constantly falling and I keep breaking
and I'm like oh my goodness when does
this personal growth thing get like just
a tad easier to where I'm not constantly
being challenged every day you know with
old concepts and ideals
so I think maybe when my life slows down
and I get more established in my like
material world when I have nothing else
to really think about that's what I'm
gonna get so restless that I'm just
gonna sit and write in my free time and
start really cranking out you know when
I get the when I get to the end of like
my emotional journey that kind of
started about year ago maybe even two
years ago what the end of like my most
recent relationship
when I feel like I've kind of reached a
pause in it or like the finality of some
of those things that I've been
struggling with I can be like okay now
that I've seen the whole thing through I
can actually piece it together and write
about it and then write about it in a
way that is current tense right and
silver lining string through all of it
because I've seen it I've seen the
finality of it I've seen the silver
lining now that I've worked through it
to a comfortable amount and so yeah just
I think I pushed myself but I don't want
to push myself in so many different
venues that I'm just exhausted and the
quality of my connections with people or
my writing or you know how I show up to
work every day is
diluted because I'm overextending myself
unnecessarily a lien on one thing but
kind of not balancing the other things
or yeah yeah I think that yeah that's
that's good that you're still like
your I think you see where you're at
you're like okay like that that is where
I'm at I mean and it's cool to think of
like I know I don't have all the answers
to like finish that chapter that needs
that's gonna tie in the whole thing
that'll make me start writing it but
just like that knowing of yeah one day I
know that's that's coming or that I I
know that I know that
I'm going to be in the position to be
the one who needs to write these things
for somebody you know
yeah writing is such a fascinating thing
I always think about like you know cuz
someday someday is all just I'm a self
self-proclaimed poet and I'll just be
I'll write some and some days I'm like
oh my god this is so sick this is the
coolest thing ever you're the coolest in
the next day I'm like what the [__] am I
talking about you know but I think that
for me I'm I've tried to like let go a
lot of my like you know I was one
identify myself like on the poet I'm a
writer and all these things but I'm like
it doesn't matter it's like what do you
do that you love just do that I think
for me I like writing and though there
are many days where it's more
frustrating them not I feel like I have
this thing like I know that I'm going to
write something that's that's very
important and I'm sharpening that tool
like maybe it's not time 65 years old
and I'm gonna write some like stupid
article it's gonna make something laugh
maybe that's what it is but like I
wouldn't I wouldn't be as good as I need
to be when I'm sixty if I don't do what
do the work I'm doing today and it's
it's both enjoyable and frustrating but
but riding man is so great I love riding
it's do you ever get the it well so this
is a sense that I say I like sorry I'm
skipping all around but yeah do you ever
get the feeling like I always say that
you don't know what the [__] you think
and tell you until you think it or you
don't know what the [__] you have to say
until you say it with riding I'm like I
could write like one subject at the top
and then I'm like I don't know what I'm
riding but before you know it you just
wrote a whole page of stuff you didn't
know it's like you start just putting
the words on paper and you start kind of
like who's doing this writing but he
seems to be figuring this out when I get
out of the way you know yeah yeah I like
that like that selfless feeling when
you're writing and it's just start it's
almost it's almost like your body your
interior knows what it needs to be set
what needs to be said what needs to fall
out on the paper but you just your job
is to get there in front of that paper
and just keep going and keep letting
yourself right and when distraction
comes up you say no we gotta get this
thing done and eventually you're in
something inside will get that thing on
the paper you know you're you're do you
have a daily writing practice now do try
to insert a daily writing practice at
all or no I don't sometimes I think well
I mean I do as of the last couple of
weeks but it's not to improve on my
writing I started doing 10 things I'm
grateful for before bed because I have I
have nightmares and extremely lazy
person in the morning I don't like being
asked to do anything that requires a lot
of thought in the morning I have a
routine very creature of habit that way
but supplementing my nightly routine
which is fluid as to when I go to sleep
it's helped my nightmares it's actually
helped me stop dreaming it's calmed me
down before bed which has been a relief
and it allows me to show up more
refreshed the next day like I'm actually
waking up before my alarm lately and I
think that's because my brain isn't like
freaking out over itself and going
through all these like nasty little
insidious thoughts I've had throughout
the day it's not even trying to digest
them anymore and if it is it's doing
them like behind a veil and it's not
it's not feeling like I need to do that
like I'm just focusing on the good and
the few dreams I have had in the last
couple of weeks they've been like quirky
but they've not been nightmares and so
I'm very I'm very pleased with how
things are doing so far that's that's a
huge thing I mean nightmares are are you
know we hear nightmares all the time
they kind of seem like a kid thing but
dude nightmares will [__] your life up
like like like if you get to the point
where you're just constantly having
nightmares you get to the point where
like I don't want to go to sleep like
it's and it's not like you're afraid to
go to sleep but it's just like what's
the point it's literally gonna make me
feel worse when I wake up I'm not gonna
feel rested I'm just going to give my
mind like a new set of energy to work on
these shitty thoughts on you know
what would you be willing to share like
a couple of like what so when you write
down ten things that you're grateful for
like or any listeners that maybe they'd
have nightmares like like what are some
kind of things that you think like oh my
house my family like what do you like to
write down I
do really little things I mean I think
when I first started trying to do
gratitude like I don't like eight months
ago I was thinking of like the big
things like I was thinking like well I'm
grateful that I'm smart and I'm grateful
that you know I'm healthy and it's like
they're so vague like it doesn't really
register in your brain like
telling yourself it's not me or that
like I almost thought about packing it
with me but so I think like last night
and almost every night I write something
about my cat cuz I'm just super grateful
for her so it surprised me Gigi
she is awesome and she's really attuned
to me and she found me as a stray and so
I just have this really unique bond with
her and so almost every day she's kind
of joining me when I go to bed she
always be around like a little shadow
and so I write something about like her
so I write like either that I'm grateful
that she is so snuggly when I'm in a bad
mood or I'm grateful that she comes to
bed with me every night or I'm grateful
for like the weird little noises that
she makes when she's sleeping or like
just like it's very it's very specific
but it's like little things like not
like I'm grateful to have her which I am
but it's why do I enjoy her why do I
enjoy the things I have and so I'll
write down like that I got to have ice
cream today or that
I was able to make a connection in a
very specific way with this student or
my hair was just they get my hair just
laid perfect this morning and there was
no struggle you know just very good
about the we get so bummed when it's
like a bad hair day but then we forget
to think a good hair day right and so
just super teeny tiny things that are
particular to that day and sometimes I
even choose things that didn't go right
that day but like it wakes me up to the
times that they have gone right and I'll
still write down you know I'm grateful
for the friends that feel comfortable
just coming over and talking when I
don't want to do anything even if I got
denied that day and someone didn't come
over it makes me think about the last
time someone did I'm like well I'm still
grateful for when it happens that's
beautiful I like that and so that's
that's my spin on it is just I take I
don't know five to ten minutes and just
whatever pops into my head I write it
down find a way to word it and like
Tencent like ten words or less purple it
and eventually I'll go back and look
through it I'm sure if I need to I
haven't so far but I try to write it
down and then let it go and then I'm
wondering if I do go back and read it
how many of them will be like repeats or
like kind of like different ways of
saying the same thing and maybe I do end
up using it for something like when
you're having a bad day and you need to
pick me up like maybe that will be like
a piece of writing at some point for me
that I use it condense hundreds of
examples of ways that I've enjoyed you
know a normal melancholy day and there's
still been good in it
and condense it in down to like an
article about like did you even bother
to think about you know how your morning
went is your hair lay down right at
someone say hi to you did someone you
know I
just like having little scraps of things
around my room in my life said I can
modify and make into something later and
when that time comes it's just like I
just know what to do with it or I just
know where that last thought was writ
down and I know which journal to go to
and I
think in a world of
in in a world of like so much
information so much content in we have
so much fed into us so much we like it
was so quick pace and we kind of break
like things are going good we just we
blast past him because like they're good
we don't have to stop we can keep going
you know but I think that when we have
things in our life or reasons in our
life to stop and be grateful for them it
kind of reminds you of like what you're
doing this all for you know like a
like a I think that if you're if you're
filling your lowest but then you're
forced to read a hundred things that
you've written in the last 50 days of
things that you literally were grateful
for that day like you're gonna pull
yourself you're gonna be like okay this
is just a thing today I am okay like
maybe I'm saying maybe it's a terrible
day I'm so a real bad day maybe lots of
bad things maybe even some of those
things in there like rewound themselves
like they don't actually equate anymore
but I think that like knowing that I'm
more than this moment like I'm more than
like I'm so exponentially sad right now
but if you have a little reference to
look at like oh yeah yesterday I had
free content awesome things happen to me
though like
in it kind of remind you of like what
what this life is all about to me like
it's like a life is not inherently good
or bad it's it's it's the things that
happen and then your reaction to it it's
it's the
it's so easy to get caught with the bad
and that's our survival technique you
know it's how the news works it's why
this is 24-hour news and we're like
constantly wanting to see these like
terrible things that happen because we
our brains that we're looking out for
ourselves and we're we're gazelles in a
field looking out for a little sound a
wrestle in the wrestle in the weeds but
when able to stop and say like oh I
didn't have lions attack me today I'm so
grateful for that or I didn't have you
know I or I got have a cat and that's so
great and like like you know because the
moments like that when you're able to
look it when you're able to like look at
your cat or your dog your animal or even
your loved one it's just somebody in
your life and like look at that
[__] and you think god you make
me laugh all the time you know you just
stare at it you just oh you make me so
happy if you let yourself really follow
those thoughts and kind of almost like
if there's bad thoughts coming up you
tell those ones no say I'm not dealing
with that right now and you just think
about the good things that nice to bring
you into a new state and I think that's
a good idea to do before you go to bed
like that yeah I can definitely think of
both my hands all the amounts of times
that I've been in a very uncomfortable
sensitive place that I've been crying
you know in the comfort of my own room
and my cats come in and done something
really obnoxious or quirky or funny and
then it turns from like a cry to a laugh
like halfway through and then just like
I'm sitting there like incessantly and
giggling with myself and like she
doesn't even realize like how silly she
looks and like she's just a cat and then
catch it yeah and it's just it's nice
and I think
sometimes we get so caught up in things
being serious that we overlook that
those moments are intended to save us
like that little thing is supposed to
throw a wrench in that for you like just
that one little thing that can happen
that can pull you out of that
seriousness it's like you need to go
with it when that happens yeah because
it's not good to stay in the sad place
in other words you have that happen in
that moment just go with it lean into it
if it's like you can never I feel like
we can never be led astray by leaning
into a good moment good moments are
gonna bring us good things are gonna
bring us better feelings they're gonna
bring us more clarity it's hard to think
critically when you're angry and you're
frustrated you're upset like you can
yeah and so at least if you're in a
positive moment you can go back to that
state of thinking clearly even if it's
like a little elated you still are
seeing things more accurately perceiving
things in a way that is beneficial to
you I think that I'm able to pull myself
out now like a you know two years ago
start doing better feeling better I
think I'm able to pull myself out now
like I can have those those little
length oh yeah you know go ahead like
you were just caught in that thought and
like oh there's a funny thing or like
you know it's not a cat for me but it's
you know something else or probably some
YouTube video or maybe I fart and
laughing my own farts for whatever I
don't know but like I think just
noticing because there is this thing in
and I used to get stuck into it and it's
a it's part of it is like you desert you
think you for me it was like oh you
deserve to feel this odd but I think
that there is this thing where when
you're sad and when you're like
like you you feel like you should stay
sad it's almost a comfort in your
sadness yeah have you ever experienced
that yeah like this and what's that all
about that's that's an interesting thing
that I always liked like I think it's
like kind of just like that cliché
phrases like misery loves company I feel
like there's something intoxicating
about feeling
feeling low
it's easy like it's easier to feel low
than it is to feel good like you I don't
know how to describe that better it is
easy yeah it I think that there's
something really beautiful about
feeling the intensity of things and I
feel like
that happens a lot more when we're sad
than it does when we're happy I think
that joy comes in so many small ways but
it's not frequent that something really
excites us and really just overwhelms us
with like positivity and enthusiasm but
when it comes to sadness it's really
easy to get overwhelmed by the intensity
of sadness and I think sometimes it's
it's almost a good thing to feel
something intensely especially if you've
been kind of living in a haze that it
can be really enticing to
spend time in that place yeah I mean
that I was just I was singing about
myself when you when it when you were
saying that just thinking about my own
like sadness
when I was on and I was like saying this
right before like if if you think you
need to get on antidepressants you
definitely should check it out this is
not every experience but antidepressants
were very very bad for me and like they
didn't help me at all it gave me this
this this feeling of nothing this like
not me feeling this in-between and again
this is not having forever tea please
like there's different ones too this is
what's my experience but um
there was a like I would do cocaine
often and that was kind of my thing I
would that would be like the one time
that out in my brain I got this is like
when you get to feel like this is when
you feel something Wiki its high of
course but even sadness you know
sometimes I think maybe we get so numbed
we get so
they could look at this feeling of like
nothing like I'm just like just this
empty sort of weird it's it's very hard
to scribe again we're talking about like
words that don't really have there's so
much more to it but it's yeah like
Courage the Cowardly Dog like there's
all this nothing and then there's their
farmhouse for all this crazy stuff half
yes yeah I mean if you're I mean maybe
if you're like I love that show so much
but if you're like living in a world
that's like that where there's nothing
going on it's like you kind of have to
like make things happen to feel things
and I think that show has a lot of like
they're trying to show like mental
illness like I think courage and is kind
of like mentally ill like he has all
these things that he's terrified of he's
so scared he has all this anxiety and
where they live like nothing should be
happening sometimes I watch that show
and I just think they're in the middle
of nowhere like is any of this really
real or is this all like just courage
like
going insane because he's so bored in
the middle of nowhere nothing's
happening
gosh yeah he's like building his own
courage out of it yeah he's you know I
want to rewatch that show from in
different lens I really like that show
cuz yeah cuz because it is kind of like
there's nothing there that there's this
nothingness but like in order to feel
something like the human the dog in that
case though whatever wants to feel
something
in for me like there was you know I
would you do cocaine to feel high or you
drink alcohol to feel I don't know numb
or laughy or whatever the heck alcohol
gives you but there's also this like
feeling sad was literally better than
feeling nothing and that's a crazy thing
and that's and that's hard to
conceptualize and I think that maybe not
a that might not make a lot of sense to
people but the feeling of nothing is
seems to me like I don't know if worse
is the right answer but it just seems so
very far different and so detached from
like the you like the human experience
is is like I would rather feel that
almost sadness then nothing weird
that's like a that's heavy
I mean people are driven insane from
like a sound of nothing being put in a
soundproof room where eventually you
start getting a tune to your blood
pulsing in your heart beating mmm the
conceptualization of nothing going on no
visual no audio that you can alter right
you know it gets really monotonous it
gets really repetitive and people are
driven and sane from being in solitary
where there's all very crazy I think
it's the worst thing we do unhealthy to
be in the dark to be where there's no
sound to be where there's no no
semblance of life aside from you it
makes you really start to like realize
how much you need outside experiences
they're going to filter in and distract
you from yourself or it yeah I think
that
nothing is terrifying like to think that
there would be nothing I think that's
why I like so many are these crazy like
folklore and beliefs because in some way
I'm like well I hope are not the only
ones like right you can we really say
that we're like the smartest things out
there I hope not you have geez I really
hope not we don't really we don't have
it figured out we just pretend we do
know I mean we've had so much time like
I mean not like us specifically but
there's been so many eras of like humans
you think we would have a lot more stuff
figured out by now I feel like we only
really started developing ways of doing
things like 150 years ago yeah I mean we
we have so much like like you go to New
York or go to any of these places like
oh my gosh humans and culture is so
amazing but then we have like the same
people who built those skyscrapers are
just like they don't understand their
own emotions which is you're born with
those it's like the first thing you
think that we would learn it's it's a
you know obviously it's it's right in my
goggles that's right where I'm at so I
see like all human emotions and we're
learning about all these things but it
kind of feels like humans as a species
are just more recently figuring out like
oh yeah where we are consciousness and
where didn't work if I can oh yeah
everything that we're saying happens
through this brain and like we're
starting to figure out that we can like
actually oh yeah all these things that
were these hands that were using to
build these giant skyscrapers like what
what the hands all about wait what's
that you know it's a it's it's a it's a
crazy-cool time to be alive that's for
sure hang it so I I can't spend like a
lot of time in my head thinking about
all of my like like I have a small
portion of it that I can serve for it
but like for my conspiracy or like my
Big Bang theories or like whatever like
I put those in like a smaller region
because I can get so overwhelmed just
trying to like piece together with what
little evidence I have or you know what
understanding I have a like time you
know I don't have enough to
conceptualize it and it makes your brain
not literally hurt but if you get really
lost really quickly yeah I do that to
myself laughing I
yeah just I've had instances in my life
where something has happened around me
or I've picked up on something that's
about to happen around me and
I've had moments of feeling like I have
some psychic abilities or I have just
like a really strong intuition or a
really weird gut feeling or something we
call it so many different things but
what it boils down to I think is why why
do we randomly understand things that
are outside our actual knowledge like
why do we sometimes randomly just have
an understanding or an awareness of
things that are typically outside of our
reach or we haven't made it there yet
and I love bounce around the idea of
like consciousness like that there has
to be something else yeah I mean there's
definitely like I think that the one of
my favorite words is wonder wonder like
I think it's it's the most important
thing like the the to me the greatest
thing you give to a kid is wonder like
yeah like I don't know man this could be
this but you're gonna have to learn for
yourself like I don't know either but
like because nothing is super solid like
we're just this whole thing we're just
assuming that we know and there's some
people that say they know but I don't
know you know I think that that having
wonder is like what because I'm someone
who likes novelty I love like learning
about like new [__] and it's a call
something new something new Oh something
new new shiny object like I love having
that wonder of like feeling right before
something conceptualizes like you're
whether it's whether it's a true thing
or whether it's like oh I can understand
how that person thinks that way or like
oh that's what that's what they mean
when they say that like okay and just
allow it like that's like one of the
most incredible things about being human
is is your ability to wonder and just
kind of like you don't really have to
have the answers and you don't have to
talk to people who have the answers but
like you nowadays you can read books and
you can watch YouTube and you can read
articles and all these things and just
you know explore your mind sometimes I
feel like when you get the answer to
something it suddenly makes it dull or
boring mm-hm and so there have been lots
of times that I have
had conversations with people and I've
had the opportunity to get an answer and
just
refrained oh and
not often but sometimes I'm just like I
feel happier being curious about this
than I would to know an absolute
yeah I think so too I think remaining in
that curious State is a cool place to be
like to wear but I mean like with this
podcast I always I always like to remain
in disbelief like a I don't fully know
what I believe I don't think anybody
does but but like
well but like just having this I'm gonna
take that on like right right at this
moment like if you're describing to me
like like your beliefs and you're like
if you were incredibly religious I would
be and you're explaining it to me and
like your truest way I would take that
in this moment think oh okay like really
I want to absorb it as deep as I can and
really try to just like okay okay so
that okay that's what you think okay you
know try to piece it together
but I'm not but you're right I'm not
looking for this like understanding of
like this final thing that I'm okay
that's that's it you can leave now
that's what I wanted you know it's not
like that its life is is
peculiar enough to where you can just
kind of remain in disbelief and kind of
maybe not fully try to wholly comprehend
things to where it's like this is the
absolute answer and I'm living my life
from this point now on but just
exploring and remaining in disbelief of
like what other people think about the
world and yeah this might be
not exactly like on note with like what
we're talking about but I think about it
from time to time often enough that it's
still you know influential something
that I'm curious about but I don't know
that I would ever want there to be
research out there
disproving that there is kind of like an
in-between for people who pass over I
don't I mean if it was like if it was
saying that there was I would not mind
that but if they're saying like an
absolute like there is no there is no
you know semblance of their soul left on
earth you know as soon as they pass
because I had this experience when I was
in third grade that my grandparents
would pick me up from Kessler on every
Wednesday and I they were late one day
and they weren't traditionally late and
I was outside and I heard
someone who sounded like like a
grandmother like just like kind of like
that grandmother voice but it wasn't my
grandmother's voice
singing my name but it sounded familiar
like I trusted in it and then I was
looking around for this person who was
like saying my name over and over again
and they weren't just saying mic and
they were saying Michael and they were
saying my full name
and like nobody calls me that and
there's literally no one in the
courtyard in the space who's looking at
me there's no adults out there who know
me you know it was just so weird and
then my grandparents pulled up and it
stopped as soon as they pulled up and so
I got in the car with them and then I
thought about it and it sounded like my
grandmother's mother would passed away
when I was like five so I guess two or
three years before that at the time and
I just kind of always have thought like
I don't know if I was just hearing
things but it was a lot it was a lot
more clear than I would have anticipated
it if I was just hearing things and I
wasn't thinking about her like I wasn't
like sitting there mourning over her
time had passed I didn't know her that
well but when I really thought about it
and I was like that sounded a lot like
her and it stopped just as soon as I
could see their car pulling in it
stopped hmm and so I don't know I don't
want there to be like research out there
that comes out that says absolutely not
that's not a possible thing like you're
it's all in your head you know I like to
remain curious about maybe that's a
possibility yeah I mean it was like
because that's that's peculiar like
hearing it and then and then where your
head was like oh is that like your
great-grandma is that would be yeah like
like in that connection like where would
that like how would you know that you
know like that's like that's an
intuition of feeling like I've like I
don't really know why I think maybe it's
this person but like it seems to make
sense or whatever um I think that I
think that a lot of times you know when
it comes to research and like facts and
all that stuff we we do get kind of you
know it's a dangerous line to just like
you can't just refute science and
indifference but like science is not the
only thing that exists science explains
a lot of like you know physics and and
there's a lot of things that really map
out but there's a lot science has no
room for spirituality science has no
room for or wonder and
IIIi don't think you know when it comes
to research and like refuting things I
don't think that like that can be taken
away because like what
like even it so so even if there's like
a paper you read a paper tomorrow and
they're like whatever they say it's like
there's absolutely no way that
essentially that there's no afterlife or
in-between or whatever like what does
that mean to you like you still have
this experience like all of a sudden
that's not real like that's so real you
believe it would just be like okay well
I think we have a lot of stuff in our
life that where we don't feel like we're
allowed to fully believe that likes
happen to us you know because there's
not like it's weird or it's like we
don't really have like a comfortable
like platform to talk about it on
but I think it's
it's like it's
important to follow those things I don't
know like do you think you think about
that moment often yeah pop up yeah I
think about it um
every couple of months or so probably
mm-hmm and I mean I've had other moments
and I kind of briefly explained to you
like my different um
my different jumps into you know I've
seen psychics I've seen mediums I've
been seen a medicine woman I've been to
a hypnotherapist like I've really tried
to dive into the parts of myself that I
don't understand in other realms that
I'm I don't know that I'm not
certain are present or not or you know
what they can bring but and all my
experiences I've found myself and just
like shocked and surprised that these
people are bringing forward things from
my subconscious they're saying things as
if they're just reading them from me hmm
and it's like I don't think that my
expression was conveying these very
specific details like the psychic that I
went and saw it was probably about five
years ago um she told my friend that she
was pregnant and that she would meet the
love of her life and such her and she
was a week pregnant and didn't know it
she got her son in September like
September early September and
she was a no way she performed thinking
that that was even a possibility and I
forced her to go and take pregnancy
tests at Walmart and she's like no I'm
not doing it and I'm like well if you
don't think it's true like if you don't
think it's a real thing then what harm
does it do to you it's like just do it
for me I'll pay for them and for plusses
and
so she also told me that there were
people in the room with us and explained
who they were and their mannerisms and
their behaviors and
she told me like directly who they were
and then explained about them and even
for one of them she said was my mom's
mom who I never met and I asked her to
describe the woman she was looking at
and I wrote down in my notes and I took
it home to my mom and I was like oh does
this sound like to you like the shape of
her nose her hair her stature her
mannerisms hurt the way she was speaking
her candor you know and my mom was like
it sounds like my mom and it was just
like I don't know I've had some kooky
experiences that I wouldn't have
believed unless I had them myself but it
just really made me open up to there's a
lot I don't understand and I may never
understand maybe that's better for my
sanity
there's so much out there that I can't
say a definitive like yeah yes there's
an answer to this er no this doesn't
possible well but I think that search to
see like to try to figure yourself out
like the fact that you went to all those
like you went to a psychic and you went
to these different things like I like to
encourage anybody to like just do like
what like if you have an intuition like
I wonder if like maybe like a psychic
would kind of like tell me what's going
on like go to a psychic I'm like all
right I'm wonder if like I I mean I I
encourage people towards like if if
religion is your forte if Christianity
isn't there's this church down the road
and like kind of someone go sit in the
back for it like dude do it please do it
if there's a if you have a friend who
like does palm readings and does tarot
cards or teru teru teru teru I don't
know esoteric I think there is a tea at
the end
but I like it dude I like Frick dude
like if you have an intuition or a
feeling in your stomach like maybe maybe
that's kind of interesting to you and
like you don't have to choose that
you're fully gonna like this is gonna
I'm gonna whatever they say I'm gonna do
and that's my life I'm like you don't
have to do that but I just think
encouraging people to like pursue these
little thoughts of like there's a reason
why you think you're kind of drawn to
certain styles of of whatever you know
for some people its energy working some
people like I said it's religion and
some people it's it's just science you
know if these you can pursue these
things and then they they have instances
where they start to make sense like I
you know what is real like real and in
in what's truth who tells you truth you
know what what the first person who made
America is he that he's either person
who says truth is truth you gotta
understand this world is complicated
listener I think I think
man I think it's super cool that you did
that I I have not been to like a psychic
or anything like that but I it
definitely fascinates me I think that
it's something like I if I was listening
on this podcast I would be someone on
the couch and go I should go check those
people out you know like what why not I
did I not go check it out and I do want
to be very clear that you know because
of my background in psychology I'm a
behaviorist by nature I like the science
I like I like some fortified out of
evidence or database or I like that you
know it's looked at in some skepticism
in that way and so when I go to these
things I go in with an open mind that
I'm not going to shut out anything that
happens and be like oh no way like I
can't handle that like that this is you
know some light tricks or whatever like
I'm not going to do that but I'm also
going to come in being a little bit
skeptical and that's why I get down to
the nitty-gritty and I've gone in and
I've tried to throw loopholes like with
first time I went to the psychic I was
in a relationship and I took off my
promise ring and I went in as though I
was single and I chose not to even
address my relationship at all and she
kept bringing it up she's like are you
in a relationship and I said no I'm not
and she's like you won't try that again
Wow and I'm like well yeah I am seeing
someone and show she's like well it's
pretty serious because grandfather is
here and he wants to talk to you oh whoa
and
and we're we were talking about him
earlier and I don't want to say his name
but his grandfather had passed away and
he was someone that he was really close
to and he talked about his grandfather a
lot to me if not more than his own
parents and so it was just interesting
that I'm like really like that family
member and he got other ones like I
don't know just so many uncanny things
that even if I went in and I tried to
liar I tried to provide reasons to be
skeptical or I asked for descriptions of
things I've just always been met with
like such transparency and such dead-on
information that I'm like I'm blown away
like I tried I didn't come in like all
googly-eyed like oh my gosh if you tell
me I'm great with animals I'm gonna be
like oh you're so psychic like
pegged and I've had those I've been to
those before but there's been some
really cool ones that I'm like you're
really perceptive in a way that I can't
explain or begin to understand because
even if my face says I'm lying and you
call me out on it like you're still
saying things after the fact that I'm
like how would you even have known right
that's that's an interesting place to be
as a human because like the one thing
like our WWE world we walk around and
live in you know our weird reality that
we like can't say our true feelings and
stuff like like it terrifies everybody
to like know that you can go into a room
and like that psychic that person or
whoever they whoever they are like they
know what's going on inside like they
know you're real things like it makes us
we're like oh I don't want that you know
that's that's probably why it's so scary
is is it's a whole level of
understanding that we don't understand
you I don't think that anyone should
enter into like a spiritual realm
without an open mind and without some
forgiveness for themselves for whatever
comes out because things might be said
or advocated for or warned I've been
warned before
that's a scary sight that's a scary word
in this you know you need to
come in just really being open-minded
and with forgiveness for yourself
because
it's it is intense and there might be
things divulged about you that you have
purposely kept from people but because
you would purposely kept them from
people they have been an obsessive
thought in your mind so they're one of
the most obvious ones to someone who can
kind of like pluck those significant is
coming for those from yourself exactly
because you're either you know you're
obsessing about fixating all the things
that you're really passionate about and
they'll be at the forefront and you'll
openly state them with people and you'll
want to talk about them in your
conversations and gravitate towards that
but there's also the things that were
like I don't want anybody to know about
this and so because they're always
thinking like keep your mouth shut you
know about this I don't bring it up or
if people bring up something relevant
like change the topic yeah
it'll I mean you're still obsessing
you're still fixating you want to make
sure that that stays hidden but you want
to be aware of it so that you never say
anything that gives part of it away yeah
it's constantly eating at you mm-hmm oh
yeah I have a
yeah I I have things in the same realm I
have the things that I was just talking
with with a couple friends Shaylee and
another friend about just stuff that
happen to my childhood and and like
realizing how often it was on my mind
before I had talked to them about it but
it's interested in think that like you
would walk into a psychic and they're
like oh I see that first thing that's
the thing that you're trying to say know
about and I see it mm-hmm it's
interesting
it's intimidating but I've walked away
with a lot of relief right but I'm like
okay someone gets it and they I don't
know just good people I don't think a
lot of people are out to be tricksters
especially if they want to like make a
business out of themselves we have Yelp
now like if you're if you're not if
you're not doing like legit business
people will yeah what is it run your
business down what are the Yelp reviews
for psychics those are probably like
pretty brutal like it's like people like
sorry I pointed out that thing you don't
like about yourself but you didn't have
to write a yelp review
right yeah I could see that being a
problem hmm
well um
you're awesome just thinking about how I
don't want to go see a psychic now I'm
like you're gonna see right through me
I'm just like nervous about not even
there Macau man what are you gonna know
about me
that's how it goes though I think that
like accepting and finding any sort of
like whatever way is calling to you and
by calling to you it's like this
intuition and by intuition it's this
it's this [__] feeling that you brush
off all the time this is little feeling
of like I wonder if like this could help
me in this area and I just I was just
again I'm just encouraging anybody to go
and check those check those things out
and try them out I got me not like
meditation and yoga is something that
like at the beginning I was really cool
and I like learning about it but I
didn't want to try it and even that is
like you follow this little intuition of
being interested in it and then it could
kind of show you things about yourself
you did mention hip hypnosis I have done
I haven't done in person hypnotism or
hypnosis but I have done on the internet
on YouTube quite a few times and I've
actually had some [__] profound
experiences with with hypnosis I have
like I have childhood trauma and so
there was a lot of that I actually had a
time where
so this wasn't directly from the
hypnosis but it was essentially Shaylee
was out of town for like three or four
days she was down in San Diego and I was
like this is this is I'm doing this I'm
doing the [__] childhood drama things
I'm gonna have a conference I'm gonna do
this I'm doing all the hypnosis is I was
like I'm going and it was right when I
was having a studio up and I actually
unbox these big big speakers behind me
and this table wasn't here but I set him
on the ground in four [__] like three
or four days I was just like smoking
crazy amounts of weed taking a ton of
CBD listening to crazy frequencies doing
like meditations hypnosis like this was
and I don't recommend people to this was
[__] insane I'm just crazy but like I
literally had in and again like so
and I'm halfway joking about this but
I'm like the way our minds work this was
a very beneficial thing like yes I was I
was super high and I was just doing yoga
and yeah I'm getting weird I'm by myself
and and whatever but like I legitimately
had experiences of you go through and
you could do like a healing trauma or
healing your inner child hypnosis sort
of things like that and I had genuine
like visions or or I made up the vision
and it seemed to work out it seemed to
help me and help me heal of seeing my
younger self and this room with me and
hugging him and saying like it's it's
okay you're done now like yeah I'll take
it from here and I had these like
profound and I just [__] cried for
four hours like I just like let go of
this terrible terrible thing that I was
holding on to I'm in a you know again
backing up to like truth and in what's
real and stuff that helped me like like
whatever the [__] that was that I did
after these hypnosis and the meditation
and whenever it helped me and like what
you know I don't have to argue with
somebody that what I saw was real it was
real to me and it helped me get through
experiences and kind of like take over
my life as a man and like let my my boy
side go no
but so that's my like I have a couple
other like crazy experiences with
hypnosis one time experienced the color
fuchsia I experienced a color purple and
I experienced it as in I was the [__]
color purple and this was I wasn't on
psychedelics this was again there was
crazy if you look up online like
binaural beats and the frequency is like
that's all a whole nother realm of like
be careful with that it's cool but you
can do too much for sure but I
experienced the color purple I hugged
myself as a younger child like these are
these are things that made me feel happy
and made me feel better in my life
that's my experience with hypnosis what
is your radical yeah do you have
anything similar to that at all or I
mean obviously this is a different this
is yoga and weed and CBD and frequencies
but that's what works for me that's just
how it helped and I don't in in and I do
well by myself and I'm pushing against
that edge now and I'm knowing when to
ask for help but that was how I got help
was with myself and YouTube but does
that continue recording even if it looks
like it's not moving yes it certainly
does yeah I know it's that the screen
catches up to it and then it's like an
apartment looking you're good I need to
take the half my episodes I take that
dang thing down so you don't have to be
distracted by it sorry about that but
next time I'll take it down to your s
jacket
so you just asked like what my
experience was yeah so that was
unfortunately like the biggest letdown
out of all the venues I've gone through
which I had the most faith in because I
was like this is science like I can
trust in the science but he I mean I
went to no therapist I think it was in
battleground
woodland battleground I don't know and
this is about four years ago and he was
male and I felt kind of nervous because
he was a man and that's just warmed from
like I felt like I was coming in because
of something that happened from a man
mm-hmm
but it took me some time and I was able
to relax and he was able to put me under
and I could feel myself half in and half
out but he said it would kind of be that
way because I would still be like
talking with him and whatnot and so he
brought me
through this garden to a door and that
was just my particular vision of it and
he'd be like okay when we opened the
door we're gonna see what it is you've
been barely burying from you know your
waking life and every time we opened
that door it would be pitch black and I
would like pekin and then as soon as I
would like blink in
that state
I wouldn't blink for real my eyes were
closed the whole time I would be back at
the start of the garden and he brought
me to that door several times and then
you know what felt like I was under for
maybe like 15 20 minutes he had me under
for like 80 minutes Wow and I think he
said that he's like we really tried to
process this a bunch of different ways
and he's like you might not remember all
of them and he was like you never got
anything he's like you saw blackness
every single time and so he told me that
that left me with two possibilities
either I'm trying to remember something
that didn't actually happen or it
happened the way I thought it happened
um or it's just so
deeply buried that I'm not ready to deal
with it yet and my body is saying like
quite literally like no leave it alone
we're not we're not addressing this
today
so I walked away from that pretty
frustrated I thought maybe there wasn't
a lot of things to be established about
it but then I had experiences after that
that made me realize that I do I do
think there's something there that I
haven't been able to access yet and then
just most recently
with like going to the medicine woman
and trying to develop like skills and
Reiki she was looking at like my field
and I can't remember what she called it
but like the space that
starts on the outside of her body and
goes to about like a foot and a half to
two feet out things that are in your
field but not a part of you um it was
kind of like she would like a look
around me like she was looking at a
computer screen and like look at
different things or like move things and
the air it's it's so interesting to like
just watch her at work
but she tore that of my visit she like
looked up at something that was like a
like above diagonal left and my field
and she's like okay but we're gonna
address that later and I was like do I
get to know what that is and she's like
you're well aware that it's there but
you're not ready to deal with it yet and
she was like when we start working on
some of like yourself feeling that you
really need to get through to establish
that that good base that good
understanding that forgiveness for
yourself then I can let you know what
that is and why you feel so
uncomfortable pretty powerful for her
you know as like a just a professional
in her field like that like whoever that
was like that seems like a pretty like
you
sturdy and powerful thing to say really
like like oh I you know I see this thing
but we're not gonna put you through that
right now you know I mean like it seems
like a very I'm just not noble thing to
say I guess it's it and I filmed
restrainer her name is melody and she's
in Vancouver and she's very sweet and
she has tons of different classes for
different reasons and she's very
personable she has these two dogs that
help her they actually do like therapy
and other pets and stuff oh my god
what's her address so she's phenomenal
but her dogs are particularly funny cuz
when she's doing her stuff at work like
they start doing these odd things and
making noises or like pawing at
different body parts while I'm sitting
there or like every time you know is so
uncanny that they are like in tune with
her like in tune with like the vibes in
the room that every time we touched on
something that was particularly pain for
me or like did strike a nerve in some
way
she's very gentle about it like it never
like I never like reacted like
emotionally but so physically and
outwardly I would not do anything except
for maybe like an expression that
indicates to her like yes like she knows
what she's talking about but every time
something was like that it happened two
or three times one of her dogs came over
and like rested his head on my knee and
only in those moments when I had that
intense emotion was he like already
walking over and like nudging me and
resting his head on my knee and being
like I'm here and so we always say dogs
know anyway right thank you that their
animals are awesome if you can really
just be
kind and compassionate towards
especially like domesticated animals
because they already kind of have those
skills in them to want to interact with
humans in a positive way you know as
much as I would love to go like hug a
raccoon and I don't think it would go
over so well baby raccoons are so cute
right baby ones yes mama ones I don't
know they're just garbage eating and but
yeah I think that I'm kind of kind of
sold on a few of the different venues
just because I've had such good
experiences that even if I didn't get to
continue any further I would recommend
it to other people awesome yeah I think
the I think that's great thanks for
sharing your experiences with both of
those for sure I think that like I
always like leading people in the
direction of like whatever is gonna heal
you like you don't we get caught up way
too quickly with what's real or what's
true or what's weird or what's whatever
like dude [__] everybody else go go
there by yourself go wherever by
yourself walk into the church by
yourself walk into the into the Reiki
healer by yourself walk walk in to the
yoga studio by yourself like whatever
whatever is like calling to you for you
to take the next stage or the next step
in your life and your healing or even if
it's not even that and it's just
something you want to check out like
just open your mind and just really try
to try your best to to walk in there
with an open mind and like maybe
experience it I feel like everyone
everyone okay I want to make a bold
enough statement I feel like everyone
can agree that the unn spontaneous
nights or days that you've had
you can recall were like some of the
best you had no expectations you had no
standards things just seemed asleep out
if things went wrong it was like
hilarious or that it wasn't like a bad
experience even though like things were
like not going with you know even the
little plan that you did have and I feel
um
how are they going with that I
totally had a connection and it was kind
of like a loose one but
rounded out was it just about how how
those situations like you think that
they're going to be a bigger deal and
they end up just being smooth and oh it
was
just simply going into things by
yourself all the opportunities that it
brings to you like if you're with
another person and you're you're you
know either matching their energy or
that you're in their bubble to and you
guys are kind of creating something
together it's not just you anymore and
it's not just what you need so you might
not get as much out of experiences if
you spend it connected with someone else
spending the whole night with them
spending evening with them when you go
to festivals I always make it a point to
run off by myself at least for a couple
hours every day because you come back to
your friends if you've all run off and
doing your own thing and everyone had
like like I mean it's easier at a
festival too because there's so many so
much going on but you all had your own
experiences some of you went off and
tried some new things some of you made
new friends some of you spent the whole
time dancing and like made like a new
romantic interest but like you all went
off and experienced different things
that or things you truly wanted to
experience and sometimes it's just being
solitary and someone went and took a nap
and it was just like the best dream they
ever had and
I've had experiences like that not quite
as fun you know just in like the normal
public here but going to a movie by
myself going to a restaurant by myself I
choose to sit at like the bar stools at
a restaurant where someone can sit next
to me or I intentionally sit next to
someone else regardless of what they
look like and I end up having really
interesting conversations with strangers
and I although I'm not always on board
for doing that and sometimes I need my
space
I would always advocate for people
trying things on their own especially if
it's something they really want to do
and they can't easily find someone to
join them instead of like rejecting the
idea because it's intimidating if you go
and do it on yourself I think like the
universe is gonna match that with
something that you're gonna find
worthwhile yeah I agree I think so it's
gonna it's gonna give you the answer I
think that person's gonna see I I I'm a
I'm a very like my DIY I'll do it myself
sort of i I always have enjoyed doing
things by myself I've always been the
like I like to wake up before other
people at the festival and go for a walk
you know or I like to like if like I did
Coachella a lot of times I would I went
with a big group we would get there and
we're at the festival and I think I'll
meet you guys and you know in three half
hours I'm gonna go cuz I'm like I really
want to follow like hi Jim you want to
see this thing you know so I'm gonna go
by myself in just that going by yourself
there's this weird feeling of like
especially if you've been like
codependent or you've always like had
somebody around or if you if you're
somebody uses your phone a lot twos even
it's like a feeling of like you think
you think people are watching you maybe
sometimes they're used to telling them
self conscious like when you're alone
it's a feeling of like like this this
gosh what is that feeling when you're
when you're like you've been with
somebody like you're always with
somebody but then you're like kind of
kind of uncomfortable but you're like I
know I want to do this alone you know I
think just if you just sit with that
feeling and you realize that it's not so
bad and you can kind of turns it into a
little dance move like it's like that
feeling that unknowing that like whoo I
don't know I want somebody with me or I
want to text somebody right now just
sitting with that feeling by yourself I
think it's good and I mean you only
when you lay your head down at night and
for a lot of sometimes part of your day
even if it's just driving like you are
by yourself like you only really have
yourself and your thoughts and your
experiences those are the only things
that you can begin to see the full scope
of your perceptions the things that are
yours and so
you have to get comfortable with pain by
yourself or like you're gonna have some
pretty
unnerving things and you're gonna I just
I feel like there was a time when I was
younger that I just had this massive
fear of abandonment that I mean was
validated I had it I know why I had it
but
it's essentially useless I mean if there
was a time that I really was abandoned
if there was this crazy plane crash when
I'm on my way to vacation and I survived
somehow and I'm by myself
with no understanding of how I'm gonna
get back to civilization
how do you make the most of something
like that like do you it comes back to
that choice do you want to survive this
to see if someone comes to rescue you or
do you give up you go down yourself and
I mean it's an option it's just just
have that breakdown choose that are you
comfortable knowing that you know five
minutes after you drown yourself a
helicopter comes and lands on the island
or as you're drowning and you're too far
out to say like I just think of things
like in really big ways sometimes but it
helps me understand that like the big
picture is all the littler pictures too
right it's you know you want to be the
survivor like why don't you I mean draw
it like castaway was like actually
brilliant like drawing a face and a
volleyball and treating it like it was
another person that saved him from
becoming insane he wasn't insane because
of it you need interaction you need
something and because maybe there wasn't
a lot of animals on the island or if
there had been they weren't you know
nice friendly animals that you can make
a pet you need to do something to keep
yourself agile keep yourself interested
in your own things your what you now
have accessible to you so that's making
this really extravagant shelter and
finding ways to do things for yourself
and building really that
that like just that like that functional
value in yourself like resilience you if
you get saved you can take that back and
teach people how to get on the tree huts
for vacations and then now you're making
money like I don't know I I don't think
I felt this way
back in high school and I definitely
didn't feel this way growing up but I
just have felt the last couple of years
that there's really no alternative for
me and I like meeting other people that
think the same way that have experienced
the lows and they've just decided there
is no alternative like no matter what
the circumstances I'm gonna choose to do
something with it and see things out to
its natural course it's natural finality
yeah I think in and we seem to always
surprise ourselves to like if you can
just get through that that discomfort
and in those moments you could just do
what you think is right and just
you'll surprise yourself like a like the
inept like if you're on an island your
plane crashed like oh my gosh can you
imagine like the terrible thoughts that
you'd have like about you got well I got
to keep going I'm not gonna drown I'm
not gonna die I'm not gonna I'm not
going to give up I mean and you're gonna
level up you're going to get better at
building huts you're gonna get better at
at whatever I mean in Tom Hanks in that
one he got better it like
he worked out I was thinking about as
you doing like the the Wilson thing I
did a lot of when I was because I I was
I wasn't I had no idea that like I was
not my thoughts like when I was like
super depressed and suicidal like I that
didn't make sense to me like I thought
that every thought that came up was like
anytime it has me I'm doing what my
thoughts say like what any time like but
when you really like taking that Wilson
and like talking to him like sometimes
you figure out what the hell you have to
say when you write it we talked about
writing like sometimes you don't know
what you're saying until you're writing
and then you're halfway through the
paper like that's what I think you know
I mean sometimes you need to make a
Wilson and you need to talk to him you
know sometimes like it like me I was
like me versus my depression like oh no
that's a depression thought that's a bad
thought Jake don't do that like let's
like what is that thought you take a
look at it you know but I
and I want to make a metaphor out of
this if someone hasn't coined it I want
to coin this
teachers talk about students needing the
tools you need the tools
materialistically to be a good learner
you need a pencil you need a paper you
need a tablet you know you need whatever
it is you need the person to teach you
who knows what they're trying to teach
you you know you can't just learn
everything from scratch you need it to
come from somewhere but you also need
you need the emotional tools to be
present and to work through things
without verbalizing it to someone else
you need to have the strength and the
confidence to seek things out for
yourself and remain curious like you
need and I want to focus on like
specifically the emotional tools you
need your emotional toolkit I tell this
with like little kids it's just how we
describe it but adults need that
emotional toolkit to survive adulthood
where you feel more alone than you
probably ever felt like even as a kid
you could have felt alone depending on
your home life but as an adult you
really see this these things happen you
end up living by yourself you end up
outside of other people and you know
even friends and family who care for you
not making a lot of time for you because
we're all going in all these crazy
different directions with different
schedules when you're alone and you
start to feel isolated and you start to
feel like people aren't making time for
you it can kind of feel like you really
are as isolated as if you're the one on
island you even if you're reaching out
to people and you're not getting hits
back or they're not calling you back
rather keep saying no I'm busy this
weekend
and if anyone's ever had a day where
they just literally could find no one to
hang out with but that's what you wanted
so badly that feeling of isolation you
like you tried and it's inconceivable
that day you need to have like on the
island you would want literal tools to
help you you would want some piece of
sharp metal that can help you cut down
trees but you would also need like your
emotional tools your mental stability to
say
this is it's not great I don't I don't
have a lot here but I have my
intelligence I have my curiosity I have
my creativity like I have these things a
part of me that cannot be taken from me
unless there's like a physical
limitation and you have you know no
capability to move yourself or strength
but you need your emotional toolkit to
get you through those random days where
you feel isolated or you feel overly
sensitive you need to keep reevaluating
within yourself not needing to ask
people like you know was this a mean
thing that someone did or am I just
being crazy you need to be able to do
that inside yourself and be like are we
just sensitive right now like we really
think that this person meant that
and do we need to address it if there's
someone that we're close to do we need
to bring this up and we're feeling more
calm about it and be like do you really
feel that way about me like where is
that coming from because it's not gonna
help our friendship sustain you know if
we don't address this yeah dude the
emotional toolkit is so important I
think do you have because I kind of have
a
I've built my emotion my emotional
toolkit is is [__] beefy and I'm
proud of my emotional toolkit like I I
have days where I just I wake up like I
said and I'm like a little I'm not good
but at my most from tool kit says like
all right bro you don't feel the best
today that's okay you got this what do
you need to do and then my emotion
toolkit I'm like alright I got a workout
I gotta do yoga I got a meditate I got
it like my emotional toolkit extends to
like things that I can do too but even
before that it's it's it's your
emotional toolkit is sometimes to me
like this voice that you add in which is
the real you to me of like this whether
it's Tony Robbins or it's Eric Thomas or
it's like one of these like intense
people like come on [__] you got
this like okay my plane crash done done
my planes crashed that's done I can't do
anything about it what's next I can do
this instead of this like oh my plane
crash what am I gonna do and you just
curl up at a ball on the ground you can
build up your emotional toolkit to where
he starts kicking in to you know he
starts like problems arise he's he's
tough you know I'm
oh gosh what's his name Ct Fletcher I
think he's a he's like one of the big
like a bodybuilder weightlifter he has
this thing he within the last couple
years he got a heart transfer in it's a
he says it's a I
so this is another strange thing he got
a heart transfer and he's a very he's a
motivational speaker he's like his thing
is that you got one more step one more
set or it's still your set if you've
ever heard that I don't know it's in the
bodybuilding world like if you're a I
don't know if you body build all the
time or what but uh it's it's it's his
thing is like you it's still your set
like if you said you're gonna do ten and
you only did eight like get back down
and do your - like it's his thing but so
he got this heart transplant yeah like
heart failure or whatever
and it and he has a think he said it was
like a young asian lady's heart and he
got and his thing is he is he when he's
feeling discouraged he doesn't feel like
he's got it or he doesn't get out of bed
or whatever he's got he says come on
Lady come on Lady we got this and talks
to his heart and that lady's heart and
he says come on Lady we got this and I
don't know if that's exactly what you
mean by emotional toolkit I was kind of
extending it into mine but it can mean a
lot of resilience I think a lot of
things are just someone's perception of
something and that's your perception of
what your emotional toolkit has to offer
unlike the ways that you've connected
with something that someone else has
utilized you know I think that's great I
think everything is very everything when
it comes to emotions it's just ambiguous
I mean so many emotions go into each
other you need emotional toolkits for
all of the things you know and we build
on our own at different levels right I I
have it I have another emotional toolkit
idea that I was thinking about okay and
I do
so on the on the inside of my glasses I
have printed lion and that's the thing
that I write on the inside of my left
hand all the time is lion a lion and
that the oh that's just an animal to a
lot of people but to me I have I've
given that word power and to me that
means like straighten up your chest back
but your put your arms back or your
chest out like you got this it's like my
like I've like given that single word
like it has so much meaning because I
have built that over time and I think
that it's like a lot of people can find
words like
you know I suppose religious people have
their have their versions of those words
that they've read I'm like okay this is
what that means and they take that on
but I think that we can make up our own
words of like like what's you know like
if your plane crashes and like like me
if I if my plane crashes and I'm on the
island and I'm like sad it's like if I
just told myself like all right lion
lion you got this your lion like that
would give me an all right man I'm super
bummed right now but the best way I'm
gonna solve this problem is if I put my
chest out and I look around I'm like
okay what are my options what are my
resources do I have a shelter like these
things lie and you know so listener if
if you're listening if you don't have a
word or a you know that mantra a lot of
times people
emotional toolkit whatever that means to
you if any of these things that we
talked about if they pop up like a dorky
idea and build that idea build it that's
more than Legos hunters are powerful do
you have any mantras or D and then also
your emotional toolkit do you have any
any of your personals that you can think
of are I utilize mantras all the time
yeah I I talked to myself in the mirror
a lot especially when I'm doing my
makeup I mean like I was a girl I got a
lot of time in front of a mirror I have
hair I have makeup I have skincare you
know I sometimes even just like to sit
in front of my mirror when I'm doing my
nails or other things or I've made that
spot in my room cozy for myself and it's
my like feel better about yourself
station so we're literally making
ourselves feel good making ourselves
feel pretty or utilizing some creativity
but also sitting there and hyping myself
up listening to get music listening to a
podcast talking to myself thinking about
what I have to do for the day and how
I'm gonna get it done I
was gonna say is that my word is has
become like grit or sissu and they're
kind of like the same thing but sissu is
uh
it's one of my
Heritage's I don't want to fudge up
which one it is it's finish I think I
believe it's finished but just to have
that grit and grit isn't being good at
anything except for not giving up
essentially it is like the act of
persistence and determination
of just seeking out better for yourself
putting your feet on the ground keep
walking keep trying keep fighting keep
learning like it's just that act of like
that total resilience to the negative
things that happen and that defiance -
like I'm not gonna let other people tell
me how to do things or bring me down and
I really like that because you can be I
mean you can be a lot of
you can be a lot of negative things
sometimes as well but I feel like even
we like every people everybody can look
at someone who doesn't give up and still
like that about them and it's so
apparent so even if you're not making a
lot of good choices in your life at that
current moment the fact that you're like
not giving up on trying to do what's
best right I mean that's really
important and so a lot of my mantras
also circle around different words that
are encompassed in those like dictionary
explanations so I will excite myself
like you arrived I'm brave I'm resilient
I'm smart I'm intelligent I am intuitive
I
really like and I think I put it in my
like a sentence about the author on
Thought Catalog is that I am a unique
and intuitive individual and those are
two of my favorite things about me is
that I really really like my ability to
connect with total strangers and get
them to open up and have deep
conversations with someone that I don't
even really know the things that most
other people know about them like I'm
really terrible with names which I feel
like sometimes clashes with like the
things that I talk about and the things
I want to bring forward into my
relationships that people think that's
such like a such an offensive thing to
forget someone's name multiple times
after meeting them but for me it's like
I could tell you what their favorite
sports team is like I could tell you
what we talked about last time I saw you
I could jump right back into that
conversation and I feel like that's way
more important and sometimes I get stuck
on the fact that people don't look like
their names we get named as babies I
feel
like I look like my name but there are
some people I meet that I just feel like
their name doesn't totally suit them
that it's not unique enough or it's not
vibrant enough or it's you know not old
fashioned enough like I think sometimes
people you know people get born at the
wrong time people get missed named so I
like to focus on the things that are
like very much like the wholesome like
they're the part of them that is them
right conversation we have were you
can't be
you can't be
ingenuine I don't know if that's a way
to listen Jen I don't know I'm genuine
this ingenuine I don't know but you
can't be that when you start having
certain like deeper level conversations
yeah so that's why I put like being
intuitive and being empathetic and being
unique are like the things that like I
would get mad and I thought about this
the other day I like the Enneagram which
opted to go into that but Enneagram says
fours are the individualist and so I
like I really pride myself on being
unique and Who I am and one of a kind
and that's super important to me and it
also like factors into like my genetic
pool like a lot of people really don't
look like me on a genetic level and so
if someone were to come to me and be
like you know you're just like everyone
else it would for me yeah I don't want
to be like everyone else um but
knowing yourself you also know that's
just not true everyone is themselves
each of us has an important job to do in
some way and you got to keep yeah Rajan
on you got to figure out what that is
and do that thing in like learning these
things about yourself and like allowing
itself to have that I'm like you know
what I do like this I honestly I don't
like being an individual like that's
fine let myself have it like just and
then learn what that's all about and
like learn how you can benefit that
thing I always talk about meditation
the thing about meditation is when
you're meditating and you notice the
moment that you notice that you've been
lost in thought you're like oh shoot
helps the pain Dishman breath that
moment that's a bicep curl that's a curl
you just boom that's you know okay I
noticed and you're back to your breath
and then you know 15 seconds later
you're like oh crap I was thinking about
my laundry again and then but that when
you're like let's go back to the breath
that's another bicep curl and I think
that
resilience and
I
finding out
like what you
finding out about yourself in in in
learning about yourself I'm sure I was
trying to relate it back to and every
time that you notice or every time you
learn about yourself it's a bicep curl
[Music]
you're strengthening your a belief and
who you are right and what you're
capable of yeah
yeah and you're building that and you're
in every time you do it it gets a little
bit stronger so like more and more
situations when you're like I don't know
what I'm all about or you're triggered
or you're set off by these different
things like when you know who you are
you don't just all the sudden wake up
one day like I know exactly who I am and
I'm going to speed I'm a hundred percent
that personnel on any interaction I come
in contact with they're gonna hit me in
the chest and I'm gonna be fine because
I Know Who I am that's not how it is you
kind of like almost figure out who you
are that's what life is and I think that
when you when you get on those things
and you're like that's who I am like I
am like grit for example you talk about
grit like
every time that you when [__] gets hard
and you kick in that voice of of I can
do this because I have grit that's a
bicep curl you know that's like every
time you do it you get a little bit
stronger and you're building yourself
into this thing but you already knew
you're this thing you're just really
stepping into it I think just doing
those bicep curls and like just doing
the doing the work of of accepting
yourself and
building where you need to build
we're getting a little up here in time I
want to make sure that we mentioned you
mentioned thought catalog can you let
listeners know where they can find you
it
so aside from like actually getting a
link which I don't know if we can attach
to like the podcast itself when you post
it I put on the Spotify or on the info
um you I would just like Google search
like my Co address thought catalog and
it'll bring you to like my author
section which there's only three of them
on there right now um still trying to
decide on that fourth and what I'm gonna
attack it and reason with it
but otherwise just downloading thought
catalog or Google searching it because
there's tons of other great articles on
there about various different things
they upload new ones every day and
they're by I would imagine some
professional writers who do it for fun
and a lot of non-professional writers I
mean sometimes I see certain names pop
up dozen or so more like times like I
know that they have books that they
publish with them too but just lots of
fresh viewpoints and faces and lots of
silver linings and ways to take the
positives out of negative scenarios and
I really appreciate it because it's
fresh it's transparent but it's also
like but we're not taking [__] lying
down like right there's got to be a
other side to this coin do you scroll
through like that sort of thing instead
of like Facebook or Instagram sometimes
again that's something that I tried when
I stopped using social media I was like
I play I replace it with reddit of
course at first and then you kind of get
to you start finding like individual
blogs that you like and it's you're kind
of absorbing that good information
rather than just kind of like the
endless entertainment sometimes that's
good yeah and I found that catalog to be
a lot more wholesome than some other
places some other places are more like
like a magazine or like they're really
into marketing things and so they'll do
like like BuzzFeed does like other
things and medium does other things and
there's nothing I can't think of but
they're they're kind of like more like
the marketing side and Thought Catalog
as far as we know doesn't pay anyone to
like submit and they don't take any
money from anyone to have their things
submitted so it's just very
come as you are someone you don't know
edits it emails you whether or not I got
accepted and then it's shared openly and
I think that's what's pretty cool about
it
cool well people definite have to check
you out on there and I'm you know in
time and I'm not trying to push you but
I look forward to to you continuing your
writing journey and I look forward to
more conversations too if you'd be
willing I think this is a great
conversation thanks for thanks for
dealing with my like not format today
you know I he got here and I'm like hey
I've been kind of sad do you want just
talk you know so I do appreciate that
mica thank you yeah this has been fun I
take some time getting used to like the
headphones on the microphone but I think
I think I've got it now like I got past
like the whole like aesthetics of the
fact that we're in a recording place
yeah I know it's I'm always telling
people yeah just grab that [__] thing
it's fine you're good in the but I get
it I get this thing you know and people
trying to like help me load my gear
they're like oh my gosh I don't want to
bump anything with this it's just people
are so sweet to me and so like in a room
a lot of times you're like I know that
like I might break something cuz I don't
know what things do I don't touch it but
thanks for getting comfortable and and
sinking into it yeah this is really
thank you for the experience and showing
an interest on having me on I really
appreciate it alright listener take care
of yourself and
work on your grit sharpen your sharpen
your grit sharpen your emotional toolkit
do your bicep curls and bring some
[__] water
you